有位名人曾说过
A famous man once said,
我们创造自己的魔鬼
"We create our own demons."
这句话谁说的 是什么意思
Who said that? What does that even mean?
都不重要
Doesn't matter.
我只是照着说罢了
I said it cause he said it.
最先说这话的已然成名
So, now, he was famous
再算上我 即两个名人都说过了这话
and it's basically getting said by two well-known guys.
我从头再说吧
I don't...I'm going to start again.
那从源头说起好了
Let's track this from the beginning.
∮ 哟 你们听 这有一个故事 ∮
∮ Yo listen up here's a story ∮
∮ 一个活在蓝色世界的小人物 ∮
∮ About a little guy that lives in a blue world ∮
∮ 白天晚上 他所见之处 ∮
∮ And all day and all night and everything he sees ∮
∮ 都只是蓝色 像他一样里外全是蓝色 ∮
∮ Is just blue like him inside and outside ∮
∮ 蓝色的房带一扇蓝色的小窗 ∮
∮ Blue is his house with a blue little window ∮
∮ 还有辆蓝色汽车 ∮
∮ And a blue Corvette ∮
∮ 对他来说都是蓝色 ∮
∮ And everything is blue for him and himself ∮
(1999年 瑞士 伯尔尼)
∮ 所有人都是蓝色 ∮
∮ And everybody around ∮
∮ 但没有人要听他说 ∮
∮ 'Cause he ain't got nobody ∮
∮ 'Cause he ain't got nobody... ∮
(新年前夕)
舞会还有半个小时结束
Half-hour 'till the ball drops.
托尼·斯塔克 你的演讲真棒
Tony Stark, great speech man!
我演讲了吗
I gave a speech?
- 那演讲如何 - 受益匪浅
- How was it?  - Edifying.
- 晦涩难懂 - 是吗？ 好评差评尽入囊中
- Unintelligible.  - Really? That's my favorite kind,
我就喜欢这调调
a winning combo.
- 我们干啥去 - 去进城找乐子
- Hey, uh, where are we going? - Uh, to town on each other,
也许会去你那儿 看看你的研究成果
probably back at your house. I want to see your research.
可以让你看研究 但是…
Okay, you can see my research, but that's...
我不打算让你看我的"下面"
I'm not going to show you my "Town".
- 斯塔克先生 我是胡英森 - 还真有人起名荡"货"
- Mr. Stark, Ho Yinsen.  - Oh, I finally met a man called "Ho".
为您介绍下我们的客人 吴医生
I'd like to introduce you to our guest, Doctor Wu.
- 吴医生 - 这位是斯塔克先生
- Oh this guy.  - Mr. Stark.
- 你好 - 你是个心脏科医生
- Hello  - You're a heart doctor.
她一会就急需看心脏病专家了
She's going to need a cardiologist after I...
- 再见 - 下次再聊吧
- Bye!  - Perhaps another time?
一切始于1999年瑞士的伯尔尼
It started in Bern, Switzerland, 1999.
想当年啊
The old days.
我从没想过会翻起这些陈年旧账
I never thought they'd come back to bite me.
为什么要旧事重提
Why would they?
你好托尼 我是阿尔德里奇·基里安
Hey Tony! Aldrich Killian,
我很喜欢你做的研究
I'm a big fan of your work.
- 我的粉丝吗？ - 他谁啊 他是说喜欢我的研究
- My work? - Who is he? He means me.
当然也喜欢您 但汉森小姐 我的组织
Well, of course, but Miss Hansen my organization
自你在麻省理工第二学年起就关注你的研究了
has been tracking your research since year two of M.I.T.
哦还是来了 让他给挤进来了
Oh wow, he made it. He made the cut.
兄弟 你去哪一层
What floor you are going to, pal?
问得恰到好处啊
Well now, that is an appropriate question.
去底层
The ground floor, actually,
就像我创办的公司一样 刚起步
of a proposal I'm putting together myself.
它是由私人投资的
It's a privately-funded
智囊团 叫"高级点子机构"
think tank called "Advanced Idea Mechanics".
两张都给她
Uh, she'll take both.
她会扔一张留一张 就不给你打电话
One to throw away and one to not call.
"高级点子机构" 简称AIM(专注) 懂了吧
"Advanced Idea Mechanics" Or AIM for short, you get it?
那当然 你T恤上不是也有么
I see that 'cause it's on your T-shirt.
喔
Oh!!
跟着大背头走 女士优先
Ladies, follow the mullet. Ladies first.
谢谢 我会打你电话的
Thank you. I'll call you.
我觉得跟你共事会很爽
I am titillated by the notion of working with you.
- 真的吗 - 等我把这些人甩开
- Yeah?  - I'll ditch these clowns.
五分钟后楼顶见
I'll see you up on the roof in five minutes.
- 我先去喝一杯润润嗓子 - 好的
- I'm just going to try to get my beef wet real quick.  - Okay.
懂我意思吧
if you know what I'm talkin' about.
待会儿见了
I'll see you up there!
不见不散
Damn betcha.
- 不是吧 还以为这只是理论 - 曾经是
- Come on, I thought that was just a theory. - Well... it was.
如果我的推论没错 大脑修复中枢可被进入
If I'm right, we can access the area of the brain
并通过化学手段被重新编码
that governs repair and chemically recode it.
太牛了
That's incredible.
简单地说 你像黑客一样
Essentially, you're hacking
黑掉了一个生命体的
into the genetic operating system of a
- 操作系统是吧 - 没错
- living organism.  - Exactly.
- 可不可以别碰我的植物 - 怎么了
- Can you not touch my plant?  - What?
它不… 她不喜欢这样
It's not... she doesn't like it. She perfers...
她和其它植物不一样
She's not like the others.
走 我们去卧室
Come on, let's go to the bedroom.
哈皮 别动她的榕属植物
Happy, leave her ficus alone.
- 由植物实验着手证明推论吗 - 暂时是的
- And you're starting with plants?  - For now, yes.
我称它为"终极改造"
I'm calling it "Extremis".
- 其实这可以　- 可以运用于人体
- Well, its... - Human application.
是的  是的  可以深层激活人体潜力
Exactly! Exactly! Dentra-degree vitalization.
预防疾病
Disease prevention.
甚至断肢再生
Even limb regrowth.
你是我见到过最有才华的女子
You're the most gifted woman I've ever met.
- 不是吧 - 仅限于瑞士
- Wow!  - In Switzerland.
- 听起来靠谱多了 - 仅限于本周
- That's better.  - This week.
你刚才差点就信了对吧
You almost bought it, didn't you?
我就说嘛 这个技术还有点小毛病
This is what I'm talking about, the glitch.
你检查过末端酶修复算法吗
Have you checked the telomerase algorithm?
- 我们没事 - 躺着别动
- We're good.  - Stay down.
你压着我了 我没事
You're right on me. I made it.
刚才什么情况
What the hell was that?
到底怎么了
我的研究出了小毛病
It's a glitch in my work.
像她说的那样 有小毛病
She was just talking about it. Glitches happen.
我还以为是千年虫呢
Oh, it's not Y2K...
嘿 新年快乐
Hey, Happy New Year!
- 新年快乐 - 新年快乐
- Happy New Year.  - Happy New Year.
好了 明早见 晚安
Alright, I'll see you in the morning, Okay? Good night.
- 你还好吧 - 挺好
- You good?  - Yep.
- 那我就在外面待着 - 好的
- I'll be right outside.  - Okay, cool.
那么 我为什么会讲这段故事
So, why am I telling you this?
因为我制造了魔鬼
Because I had just created demons.
却毫不自知
And I didn't even know it.
(你知道我是谁)
当年纵情声色
Yeah, those were good times.
但时光不再
Then I moved on.
我在阿富汗某山洞吃了些苦头
After a brief soiree in an Afghan cave,
此后戒绝了宴会派对
I said "Goodbye" To the party scene.
也忘了在瑞士的那一夜
I forgot that night in Switzerland.
(现在 加利福尼亚 马利布)
如今 我脱胎换骨
These days I'm a changed man.
改变了很多
I'm different now.
我是…
I'm...
哦 你知道我是谁
well, you know who I am.
先生 请允许我先花几小时
Sir, please, may I request
- 来调整一下… - 没门儿
- just a few hours to calibrate...  - Nope!
微型中继设备植入完毕
Micro-repeater implanting sequence complete!
如您所愿 先生 我还准备了
As you wish, sir. I've also prepared a
详尽的安全手册让您来无视
safety briefing for you to enitrely ignore.
安心 我肯定无视
Which I will.
好 来试试吧
Alright, let's do this.
小笨
Dummy.
笨笨 你怎么戴上那顶帽子的
Hi Dummy. How did you get that cap on your head?
跟你很配
You earned it.
喂 喂
Hey. Hey!
你在角落里干了什么好事 你自己清楚
What are you doing out of the corner? You know what you did.
把毯子上的血弄干净
Blood on my mat, handle it.
先生 您差不多72小时没合眼了
Sir, may I remind you that you've been awake for nearly 72 hours.
听好了 女士们 晚上好
Focus up ladies. Good evening
欢迎光临"产房"
And welcome to the birthing suite.
我很荣幸地向你们宣布
I am pleased to announce the imminent arrival
你们牛逼哄哄且生机勃勃的小弟弟就要诞生啦
of your bouncing, badass baby brother.
启动摄像机开始录像 加时间和日期戳
Start titan and go white. Stamp date and time.
第42代 自动推进附着战衣测试开始
Mark 42 autonomous prehensile propulsion suit test.
启动程序
Initialize sequence.
贾维斯 来点儿音乐
Jarvis, drop my needle.
靠
Crap.
好 应该没问题了 一起上吧
Alright, I think we got this. Send them all.
有点儿快了 慢点儿吧
Probably just a little fast, slow it down.
就不能缓和…
Slow it down just a...
一点点儿么
little bit.
贾维斯 让它们安分点吧
Cool it, will you Jarvis?
来啊
Come on.
我才不怕你
I ain't scared of you.
我最厉害了
I'm the best.
看您工作真是让我一如既往好开心呢
As always sir, a great pleasure watching you work.
足足3天3夜没怎么休息
I guess 72 hours is a long time between siestas.
没想到情况会越来越糟
Didn't think it could get any worse.
一打开电视
Then they had to go and turn on the TV.
就能看到"他"正抢着新闻
That's when 'He' happened.
有人说我是恐怖分子
Some people call me a terrorist.
但我觉得自己是老师
I consider myself a teacher.
美国…
America...
准备好再上一课吧
Ready for another lesson.
1864年 在科罗拉多州的桑德克里克地区
In 1864 in Sand Creek, Colorado.
美军趁着
The U.S. Military waited until
淳朴的夏安族族中勇士都外出打猎时
the friendly Cheyenne Braves had all gone hunting.
伺机屠杀了留守的老幼妇孺
Waited to attack and slaughter the families left behind.
并占领了他们的土地
And claim their land.
39小时前 美驻科威特的阿里艾尔萨勒姆空军基地遭袭
39 hours ago, the Ali Al Salem Air Base in Kuwait was attacked.
是我干的
I did that.
奇怪的军队教堂里
A quaint military church,
挤满了妇女和儿童
filled with wives and children of course.
士兵都外出演习去了
The soliders were out on manuvers.
也就是说 "勇士"都不在家
The "Braves" were away.
埃利斯总统 你一直都在
President Ellis, you continue
抵制我对你的教育
to resist my attempts to educate you, sir.
而现在 又想起我了吧
And now, you've missed me again.
你知道我是谁 却不知道我在哪里
You know who I am. You don't know where I am.
也永远料不到我要干什么
And you'll never see me coming.
…信号好像恢复了
... and now that we seem to be back,
我们回顾下视频中的恐怖袭击
let's recap some of the frightening developments in this story.
美国航空公司遭到劫持
American airways were hijacked.
全国高度戒备
The nation remains on high alert.
所有寻找曼达林的行动
All attempts to find Mandarin
都宣告无果
have so far proved unsuccessful.
我的内阁积极应对此次恐怖事件
Central to my administration's response
并将起用全新人力和物力进行反击
to this terrorist event is a newly-minted resource.
他就是詹姆斯·罗迪上校
I know him as Colonel James Rhodes.
美国人民很快就会熟知这位钢铁爱国者
The American people will soon know him as the Iron Patriot.
埃利斯总统就这么应对的？
And how is President Ellis responding?
把以前的"战争机器"
By taking the guy they
拿出来重新刷了遍漆而已
call "War Machine" and giving him a paint job.
还是那套战衣 但涂成了红白蓝三色 你们看
The same suit but painted red, white and blue, look at that.
然后名字变了 叫钢铁爱国者
And they've also renamed him Iron Patriot.
以免漆薄了让人认出原形
You know, just in case the paint was too subtle.
民意反馈结果还挺好的 不是吗？
It tested well with focus groups, alright?
- 我竟成了钢铁爱国者 - 听着
- I am Iron Patriot. - Listen.
战争机器听着太强势
War Machine was a little too aggressive, alright.
这个名字好一点
This sends a better message.
那曼达林到底是怎么回事
So what's really going on? With Mandarin.
说正经的 能和我说一下这家伙么？
Seriously, can we talk about this guy?
这是机密情报 托尼
It's classified information, Tony.
- 好吧 有九起爆炸 - 九起
- Okay, there've been nine bombings. - Nine.
公众知道的只有三起
The public only knows about three.
但现在问题是 不知道爆炸装置是什么
But here's the thing... nobody can ID a device.
- 现场弹壳都没有 - 我帮得上忙 随时找我
- There's no bomb casings.  - You know I can help. Just ask.
我有大堆新发明 有自动附着战衣 还有
I got a ton of new tech. I got a prehensile suit. I got.
排弹装置
Bomb disposal.
可在半空拦截弹药
Catches explosions mid-air.
你多久没睡个好觉了？
When's the last time you got a good night's sleep?
爱因斯坦一年才睡三个小时 成就比我高多了
Einstein slept three hours a year. Look what he did.
大家都很担心你 托尼
People are concerned about you, Tony.
我也很担心你
I'm concerned about you.
- 你要打感情牌么？ - 不是
- You gonna come at me like that?  - No.
我不想让你觉得我是笨-
Look, I'm not trying to be a dic-
- 蛋 - 可以在我的画上签个名么？
- tator. - Would you mind signing my drawing?
只要他不介意就行 你不介意吧 笨蛋
If Richard doesn't mind. You alright with this, Dick?
我没问题
Fine with me.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 埃琳
- What is your name? - Erin.
你很像圣诞故事里的男一号
I loved you in A Christmas Story, by the way.
国防部那帮人害怕了
Listen, the Pentagon is scared.
纽约事件外星人事件 拜托
After New York, aliens, come on.
他们得假装强大
They need to look strong.
现在最要紧的是阻止曼达林 但不…
Stopping the Mandarin is a priority, but it's not...
不关超级英雄的事
It's not superhero business.
- 是的 确实无关 - 明白了
- No, it's not. Quite frankly.  - Get it.
说实话 这是全国上下所有人的事
Quite frankly, it's American business.
所以我才说 我… 明白了
That's why I said. I... got it.
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
我弄断了蜡笔
I broke the crayon.
你还好吗 斯塔克先生？
Are you okay, Mr. Stark?
放松点 托尼
Take it easy. Tony...
你是怎么从虫洞里出来的？
How did you get out of the wormhole?
- 等等 托尼 - 他说什么？
- Wait a minute, Tony.  - What did he say?
抱歉 我得看一下战衣 确保… 好了
Sorry. Have to check on the suit... make sure... okay.
检查心脏 检查 检查下 是大脑么？
Check the heart, check the, check the, is it the brain?
心脏和大脑都没有异常
No sign of cardiac analomy or unusual brain activity.
那我是中毒了么？
Okay, so I was poisoned?
我的诊断是 您目前有严重的焦虑症
My diagnosis is that you've experienced a severe anxiety attack.
我吗？
Me?
兄弟 这样可不好 快出来
Come on man, this isn't a good look. Open up.
抱歉 我先走一步了
Sorry, I gotta split.
胸牌 胸牌
Badge... Badge...
戴胸牌
Badge.
戴胸牌啊 洗手间还贴了备忘条呢 拜托
Badge, guys. I put a memo in the toliet, come on.
托尼把它们放在地下室
Tony has got them in his basement,
机器人戴着派对帽 都可以投入使用
they're wearing party hats, this is an asset we can put to use.
是么 那你是建议我
Uh-huh. So, you're suggesting that I replace
把所有家政人员都换成机器人么？
the entire janitorial staff with robots?
我只是说 用人的部分可用机器代替
What I'm saying is that the human element of Human Resources
人比机器脆弱得多 也是我们最大的弱点
is our biggest point of vulnerability.
最好马上行动 除去弱点
We should start phasing it out immediately.
- 什么？ - 抱歉 班比
- What!?  - Excuse me, Bambi
- 你刚那么说了么？ - 安保胸牌
- Did you just say that?  - Security.
哈皮 我为你成了安保部主管感到很开心
Happy, okay, I am thrilled that you're now the Head of Security.
- 这个职位非常适合你 - 谢谢
- Okay, it is the perfect position for you. - Thank you.
- 但是 - 非常感谢
- However... - I do appreciate it.
- 你接任以来 - 不用和我说谢谢
- Since you've taken the post,  - You don't have to thank me.
员工投诉率升高了300%
We've had a rise in staff complaints of 300 percent.
- 谢谢 - 这不是夸奖
- Thank you. - That's not a compliment.
"这不是夸奖"？ 这当然是在夸我
"That's not a compliment"? It is a compliment!
显然某人是在掩饰
Clearly somebody is trying to hide something.
- 打扰一下 - 什么事？
- Excuse me. - Yes?
珮珀小姐 您约在四点的客人到了
Miss Potts, your four o'clock is here.
四点的约 你和我确认过么？
Did you clear this four o'clock with me?
哈皮 咱们稍后再谈
Happy, we'll talk about this later.
我眼下得去处理一件非常麻烦的事
But right now I have to go deal with this very annoying thing.
怎么说？
How so?
我和他共事过 以前就总想和我约会
I used to work with him, and he used to ask me out all the time,
所以有点难办
so it's a little awkward.
光听就觉得棘手
I don't like the sound of that.
- 珮珀 - 基里安？
- Pepper.  - Killian?
你看上去不错
You look great.
很漂亮
You look really great.
天哪 你 你很帅气啊
God, you, you look great.
我… 我难以… 你之前到底在做什么？
I, I, I can't...  What on Earth have you been doing?
没什么
Nothing fancy,
五年都在接受理疗
just five years in the hands of physical therapists.
还有 叫我阿尔德里奇就好
And please, call me Aldrich.
你没领安保胸牌吗？
Uh, you were supposed to be issued a security badge?
哈皮 没事的
Happy, it's okay.
- 什么？ - 不会有什么事
- Yes?  - We're good.
- 你确定？ - 当然
- You sure?  - Yes.
- 你先去吧 - 我就在附近 不会走远
- Stand down.  - I'm going to linger. Right here, okay.
见到你真高兴 基里安
It's very nice to see you, Killian.
嘿 伙计
Hey, guy.
圣诞节快乐
Merry Christmas.
这些年 我的智囊团
After years dodging the
一直在规避"非道德生物研究"禁令
president's ban on "Immoral Biotech Research",
并研发出了一个小玩意儿
my think tank now has a little something in the pipeline.
命名为"终极改造"
It's an idea we like to call "Extremis".
让我先把灯关上
I'm gonna turn your lights down.
请参观人类大脑
Regard the human brain.
等下 不对 这是宇宙 我弄错了
Uh, wait, hold on, hold on, that's, that's the universe, my bad.
应该是这个…
But if I do that...
这就是人脑
That's the brain.
仿真效果不可思议吧？
Strangely mimetic though, wouldn't you say?
很神奇!
Wow, that's amazing!
谢谢 这是我的大脑
Thanks, it's mine.
什么？
What?
你看到的是我大脑深处 和实况转播一样
This... you're inside my head. It's a live feed.
上来 我演示给你看
Come on up, I'll prove it to you.
来啊
Come on.
现在掐我胳膊一下 我不怕疼 掐啊
Now, pinch my arm. I can take it. Pinch me.
那是什么
What is that?
这是初级体感皮层
The primary somatosensory cortex.
也就是大脑的痛觉中心
It's the brain's pain center,
但这里…这里才是我想给你看的
but this... is what I wanted to show you.
目前 "终极改造"项目正开发人体生物电潜力
Now, "Extremis" harnesses our bioelectrical potential.
并将其送到这里
And it goes... here.
而这里空间充足 也就是说
This is essentially an empty slot, and what this tells us is that
人类的大脑和DNA系统 注定要升级换代
our mind, our entire DNA in fact, is destined to be upgraded.
哇哦
Wow.
- 喂？ 我是安保头子 - 什么？
- Hello? This is forehead of Security.  - What?
别闹 我正经上班呢 你干嘛？
You know, look, I got a real job. What do you want?
我在忙 有事
I'm working. I got something going on here.
什么事？ 烦人的实习生吗？
What? Harassing interns?
我和你说 如果我告诉别人
Let me tell you something, you know what happened
自己当过钢铁侠的保镖 你知道会怎样吗？
when I told people I was Iron Man's bodyguard?
他们会大声嘲笑我
They would laugh in my face.
而我得在脸没丢光前赶快开溜
I had to leave while I still had a shred of dignity.
现在我有正经事做 保护珮珀
Now I got a real job. I'm watching Pepper.
出了什么事？ 快告诉我
What's going on? Fill me in.
- 你真想知道？ - 当然啊
- For real?  - Yeah.
好吧 她正在和
Alright, so she's meeting up
一个高帅富科学家会面
with this scientist rich guy, handsome.
刚开始我没认出他来
I couldn't make his face at first, right?
你也知道我认人很厉害的
And you know I'm good with faces.
- 对 这方面你最强 - 所以我查了他的资料
- Oh yeah, you're the best. - Yeah, so I run his credentials,
认出他是阿尔德里奇·基里安 我们还见过这家伙呢
I make him. Aldrich Killian. We actually met the guy back in...
1999年科学大会 当时在哪儿来着？
Where were we in '99? The Science Conference?
呃 瑞士
Uh, Switzerland.
对对 就是那儿
Right, right, exactly.
基里安 我完全没印象啊
Killian, I don't remember that guy.
你当然没印象了 他又不是金发大胸女
Of course you don't remember, he's not a blonde with a big rack.
刚开始还好 他俩在谈正事 可现在
At first it was fine, they were talking business, but now
气氛很奇怪 他正给珮珀展示他的大脑
it's like getting weird. He's showing her his big brain.
- 他的什么？ - 大脑 她还挺喜欢
- His what? - Big brain, and she likes it.
你自己看看吧 等一下 看见没？
Here, let me show you. Hold on. See?
看什么？ 看你盯着他们吗
Look at what? You watching them?
把屏幕转过去
Flip the screen
- 我就能看到了 - 我没你懂科技
- and then we can get started.  - I'm not a tech genius like you,
相信我 赶快过来吧
just trust me, get down here.
转下屏幕我就知道怎么回事了
Flip the screen, then I can see what they're doing.
我又不知道怎么转屏幕!
I don't know how to flip the screen!
别对我指手画脚 你已经不是我老板了
Don't talk to me like that anymore. You're not my boss.
总之我不为你工作 而且这哥们很可疑
Alright, I don't work for you, and I don't trust this guy.
他带来的人也鬼鬼祟祟的
He's got another guy with him, he's shifty.
放松 你只需要确保周边安全就可以
Relax. I'm just asking you to secure the perimeter.
让他去外面喝杯东西什么的
Tell him to go out for a drink or something.
知道吗？ 你最好多关心关心
You know what? You should take more of an interest in
这里的情况
what's going on here.
这女人是你最该珍视的
This woman is the best thing that ever happened to you.
- 你却总忽视她 - 巨型大脑？
- And you're just ignoring her.  - A giant brain?
对啊 还有一个鬼鬼祟祟的家伙
Yeah, there's a giant brain, there's a shifty character...
我得跟踪他 仔细调查他
I'm going to follow this guy. I'm going to run his plates
就算闯祸也无所谓
and if it gets rough, so be it.
我很想你 哈皮
I miss you, Happy.
我也想你 想念以前的你
Yeah, I miss you too but the way it used to be.
如今你和重量级朋友混
Now you're off with the 'superfriends'
我都不知道你近况了
I don't know what's going on with you anymore.
世界也越来越奇怪
The world's gettin' weird.
- 抱歉 打断一下 你带电击枪了吗？ - 干嘛？
- Hey I hate to cut you off, do you have your taser on you? - Why?
貌似人事部有个女的
I think there's a gal in HR who is trying
在偷墨盒
to steal some printer ink.
你最好过去给她一击
You should probably go over there and zap her.
好嘞
Yeah, nice.
想象下 你能黑掉任何生物的硬盘
Imagine if you could hack into the hard drive of
并给它的DNA重新编码
any living organism and recode its DNA.
那可真棒
It would be incredible.
可惜 它也极可能运用于武器
Unfortunately, to my ears it also sounds highly weaponizable.
像超能战士 私军之类的
As in enhanced soldiers, private armies,
- 托尼不会对这些… - 托尼 托尼
- and Tony is not...  - Tony, Tony.
其实我邀请过他 加入AIM
You know, I invited Tony to join AIM.
13年前的事了 当时他拒绝了我
13 years ago and he turned me down.
可现在不一样了
But something tells me now there
另有天才执掌高位
is a new genius on the throne,
她不归托尼管
who doesn't have to answer to Tony anymore
也不像他那般自大
and who has slightly less of an ego.
尽管我很想帮你 阿尔德里奇
It's going to be a no, Aldrich...
但我还是得拒绝你
as much as I'd like to help you.
说实话 我很失望
I can't say that I'm not disappointed,
但就像我父亲说过的
but as my father used to say,
"透过失败的迷雾能看到成功的曙光"
"Failure is the fog through which we glimpse triumph."
很深奥 我都没听懂什么意思
It's very deep, and I have no idea what it means.
我也不明白 我老爸也就是个傻子
Well, me meither, he was kind of an idiot, my old man.
我们还会再见面的 珮珀
I'm sure I'll see you again, Pepper.
哈皮
Happy!
车准备好了…随时可以出发
The car is ready... if you're ready to go.
好的 天哪 我忘了我还有点事儿…
Yes, I just um, God, I forgot my other thing so I'm just gonna...
(珮珀 圣诞快乐)
对不起我迟到了 我刚才…你干嘛啊？!
I'm sorry I'm late. I was.. What is that?!
你在家里也穿着它？ 这是第15代吗？
You're wearing this in the house now? What is that, like Mark 15?
对 差不多 每个人都有自己的爱好
Something like that. You know, everybody needs a hobby.
非得穿着它在客厅显摆爱好咯？
Oh, and you have to wear your hobby in the living room?
我就是穿着习惯一下
Just breaking it in, you know,
刚开始穿包得有点紧
it's always a little pinchy in the GUI-bagger at first.
嘿 看到给你的圣诞礼物没？
Oh hey, did you see your Christmas present?
看到了 怎么会看不到呢
Yes, I did. I don't know how
那么大的圣诞礼物
I could have missed that Christmas present.
搬得进来吗？
Is it gonna fit through the door?
嗯 问得好 我找了一伙人
Well actually, uh, that's a good question, I got a team of guys
他们明天会过来把这面墙炸掉
coming tomorrow. They're gonna blow out that wall.
今天过得好不好？ 累吗？
So, uh, tense? Good day?
肩膀有点儿紧啊 不乖哦
Oh shoulders, a little naughty. Naughty girl.
别嫌我啰嗦 只想知道 你喜欢那大兔子吗？
I don't want to harp on this, but did you like the custom rabbit?
问我喜不喜欢？
Did I like it?
- 超喜欢吧？ - 哇哦
- Nailed it, right? - Wow.
我很感激你的心意
I appreciate the thought very much.
你为什么不能把面具摘了 吻我一下呢？
So why don't you lift up that facemask and give me a kiss?
糟糕 打不开它
Huh, yup, damnit. No can do.
不然你就冲这个缝儿来一口？
You want to just kiss it on the, uh, facial slit?
我还是去车库看看吧
Why don't I run down to the garage and see if
找撬棍撬开这玩意儿
I can't find a crowbar to jimmy that thing open?
撬棍？ 啊别去 那里有辐射泄漏
A crowbar? Yeah. Oh, except there's been a radiation leak.
- 我愿意冒这个险 - 很危险的
- I'll take my chances.  - That's risky.
好歹穿上生化防护服
At least let me get you like a Hazmat suit.
或者测完放射指数什么的再去
Or a Geiger counter or something like that.
- 被发现了 - 这真是达到了无聊的新境界
- Busted.  - This is a new level of lame.
- 抱歉 - 你约我吃晚饭 却不等我 自己先吃了？
- Sorry. - You ate without me, already? On date night?
- 他只是… - 是你吧
- He was just. - You mean you.
对 是我 我只是想说我们刚刚…
Well yeah, I just mean we were just...
一边招待你 一边完成了点工作
just hosting you while I finished up a little work.
嗯哼…
Uh Huh..
我之前随便吃了点
And yes, I had a quick bite.
因为不知道你到底是回家呢
I didn't know if you were coming home
还是和基里安出去
Or you were having drinks with Aldrich Killian.
- 什么 - 啥
- What?  - What?
基里安？ 你监视我吗？
Aldrich Killian? What are you checking up on me?
- 哈皮是关心你 - 不 你在监视我
- Happy was concerned.  - No, you're spying on me.
- 我去睡觉了 - 等等 别这样 珮珀
- I'm going to bed. - Hold on. Come on. Pep-
我承认 是我错了 对不起
Hey, I admit it! My fault. Sorry.
我现在一团糟
I'm a piping hot mess.
这阵子都这样…还没和人说起过
It's been going on for a while... I haven't said anything.
- 从纽约事件起就这样了 - 是吗
- Nothing's been the same since New York. - Oh really?
我完全没注意到
I didn't notice that, at all.
经历过一些事
You experience things and then
事情了了 却还是无法讲清始末
they're over and you still can't explain them.
神灵 外星人 其他次元…而我只是藏身铁壳的人类
Gods, aliens, other dimensions... I'm just a man in a can.
我之所以还没崩溃
The only reason I haven't
只因为你搬进来了
cracked up is probably because you've moved in.
这实在太好了 我真幸运 我爱你
Which is great. I love you, I'm lucky.
但亲爱的…我睡不着
But honey... I can't sleep.
你睡了 我就到这里来干干活 修补修补盔甲
You go to bed, I come down here. I do what I know, I tinker.
威胁逼近
The threat is imminent.
我必须守护最重要的珍宝
And I have to protect the one thing that I can't live without.
那就是你
That's you.
至于我的盔甲 它们是…
And my suits, they're uh...
- 机器 - 它们是我的一部分
- Machines. - They're part of me.
- 你在转移我注意 - 可能吧
- A distraction.  - Maybe.
- 我去洗个澡 - 好
- I'm gonna take a shower. - Okay.
- 你也一起 - 很好
- And you're going to join me. - Better.
托尼
Tony!
托尼 托尼
Tony! Tony!
关闭电源
Power down!
我肯定是在梦里召唤了它 这一切不该发生的
I must have called it in my sleep. That's not supposed to happen.
我去重新校对下传感器
I'll recalibrate the sensors.
我们可以…让我…让我
Can we just...just let me...just let
喘口气 好吗 别走好不好 珮珀
me catch my breath, okay? Don't go, alright? Pepper?
我去楼下睡 你一个人修吧
I'm going to sleep downstairs. Tinker with that.
- 你控制的住么 - 我可以的
- Can you regulate? - Yes, I can regulate.
- 确定？ - 确定
- Are you sure about that?  - Yes.
这批货很不错
It's a decent batch.
- 别说我没关照你 - 多谢
- Don't say I never did nothing for you. - Thank you.
多谢理解
I mean for understanding.
不好意思 伙计
I'm sorry, buddy.
你在干嘛 伙计
What're ya doing, buddy?
自己闲逛呢 还是出来约会
You out by yourself? A little date night?
看你最爱的肥皂电影么？
Watching your favorite chick flick maybe?
对 电影名叫"派对结束"
Yeah, a little movie called "The Party's Over"
由你和你嗑药的女友出演 票在这儿呢
Starring you and your junkie girlfriend, and here's the ticket.
别开玩笑 这不是你的
No kidding. That doesn't belong to you.
赛文 救我 救命
Savin! Help! Help me!
这是关于幸运饼干的真实故事
A true story about fortune cookies.
它们看着很中式 听着很中式
They look Chinese. They sound Chinese.
却的确由美国人发明
But they're actually an American invention.
所以饼馅空心 充满了谎言
Which is why they're hollow, full of lies,
味道也不好
and leave a bad taste in the mouth.
我的门徒刚摧毁了另一个廉价的美国仿制品
My disciples just destroyed another cheap American knock-off.
中国大剧院
The Chinese Theater.
总统先生 我知道这让人消沉
Mr. President. I know this must be getting frustrating.
但这一季的恐怖剧目要落幕了
But this season of terror is drawing to a close.
不过别急 重头戏即将开演 你的毕业典礼
And don't worry, the big one is coming, your graduation.
- 嗨 - 噢
- Hi. - Oh, uh.
- 不介意电视开着吧 - 不介意
- Mind leaving that on? - Sure.
PBS的周日晚间剧《唐顿庄园》
Sunday night's PBS, "Downtown Abbey"
是部电视剧 他很喜欢
That's the show. He thinks it's elegant.
再拜托件事 让所有人戴好胸牌
One more thing, make sure everyone wears their badges.
因为他注重细节
He's a stickler for that sort of thing,
还有我的人也不会让没胸牌的人进来
plus my guys won't let anyone in without them.
我们在等待托尼·斯塔克的到来
We're awaiting the arrival of Tony Stark.
希望他能做出回应
We're hoping he'll give us the reaction.
回应最近的一次恐怖袭击
His reaction to the latest attack.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark!
有消息称 这次袭击也由曼达林策动
Our sources are telling us that this is another Mandarin attack.
您还知道其他细节吗
Anything else you can tell us?
斯塔克先生 什么时候除了这个恶棍
Hey Mr. Stark! When is somebody going to kill this guy?
说点吧
Just sayin'.
你们那么想知道？
Is that what you want?
我有个小小的节日问候
Here's a little Holiday
想要送给曼达林
greeting I've been wanting to send to the Mandarin.
我刚想好了措辞
I just didn't know how to phrase it until now.
我叫托尼·斯塔克 你并不可怕
My name is Tony Stark and I'm not afraid of you.
因为你不过是懦夫 我准备好了
I know that you're a coward, so I've decided
你等着受死吧 伙计
That you just died, pal.
我会手刃你
I'm gonna come get the body.
不牵涉政治 我是为了私仇要报复你
There's no politics here, it's just good old-fashioned revenge.
也和国防部无关 是咱俩的私人恩怨
There's no Pentagon. It's just you and me.
堂堂正正地较量吧 这是我家的地址
And on the off-chance you're a man, here's my home address:
马里布港10880号 邮编90265
10880, Malibu Port, 90265.
敞开门欢迎你
I'll leave the door unlocked.
你满意了吧
That's what you wanted, right?
告我吧
Bill me.
先生 我为您编好了曼达林的数据库
I've compiled a Mandarin database for you, sir.
根据神盾局 联邦调查局和中情局截获的情报
Drawn from S.H.I.E.L.D., F.B.I. And C.I.A. Intercepts.
开始虚拟重建犯罪现场
Initiating virtual crimescene reconstruction.
好了 我们来看看
Okay, what do we got here?
"他被称为幕僚"
"His name is an ancient Chinese war mantle"
"意思是首领的顾问"
"Meaning 'Advisor to the King'."
"南美叛乱策略"
"South American insurgency tactics."
"说话口气像浸信会传教士"
"Talks like a Baptist preacher."
这里信息太多了 看不过来
There's lots of pageantry going on here, lots of theatre.
- 关闭 - 爆炸导致的高温超过了3000℃
- Close. - The heat from the blast was in excess of 3000 degrees Celsius.
能迅速蒸发方圆12.5码内的一切东西
Any subjects within 12.5 yards were vaporized instantly.
中国大剧院周围
No bomb parts found in a
- 三英里内没发现任何炸弹残骸 - 对的 先生
- 3-mile radius of the Chinese theatre. - No, sir.
告诉我 哈皮
Talk to me, Happy.
不是炸弹的炸弹 是什么
What is a bomb not a bomb?
- 有军人受害么 - 根据公共数据 没有 先生
- Any military victims? - Not according to public records, sir.
再调出温度分布图
Bring up the thermogenic signatures again,
把3000℃这个因素也考虑进去
factor in 3000 degrees.
甲骨文云计算已完成分析
The oracle cloud has completed analysis.
现在开始访问卫星
Accessing satellites and plotting
绘制出过去12个月的热能事件
the last 12 months of thermogenic occurances now.
排除曼达林袭击过的地点
Take away everywhere that there's been a Mandarin attack.
(加利福利亚州 圣拉斐尔 1310°)
不是
Nope.
(密苏里州 斯普林菲尔德 870°)
(田纳西州 玫瑰山 3000°)
就那个了
That.
你确定那个不是他干的？
You sure that's not one of his?
时间上早于任何已知的曼达林袭击事件
It predates any known Mandarin attack.
该事件是引爆炸药自杀
The incident was the use of a bomb to assist a suicide.
拉近点
Bring it around.
热能特征近似 都是3000摄氏度
The heat signature is remarkably similar. 3000 degrees Celsius.
是俩个军人
That's two military guys.
去过田纳西州吗 贾维斯
Ever been to Tennessee, Jarvis?
准备飞去田纳西州
Creating a flight plan for Tennessee.
怎么还有人来敲门
Are we still at 'Ding-Dong'?
我们应该全副安全防范啊
We're supposed to be on total security lockdown.
拜托 我刚威胁了一个恐怖分子 谁啊
Come on, I threatened a terrorist. Who is that?
先生 我只能帮到这里了
There's only so much I can do, sir,
谁叫你公布了自家的地址
when you give the world's press your home address.
就站在这里
Right there's fine.
你不是曼达林 对吗? 你是么?
You're not the Mandarin, are you? Are you?
你不记得我了 我竟然一点也不意外
You don't remember. Why I am not surprised?
不是只对你这样
Don't take it personally,
我连自己早饭吃了什么都不记得
I don't remember what I had for breakfast.
- 先生 无谷华夫饼干 - 对头
- Gluten-free waffles, sir. - That's right.
我得和你谈谈
Look, I need to be alone with you,
换个地儿吧 这事很急
someplace not here... it's urgent.
放以前 我会顺势而上
Normally, I'd go for that sort of thing,
但现在不会了 我有正式的女朋友了
but now I'm in a committed relationship.
- 就…是她 - 托尼
- It's... with her.  - Tony
- 有人来了吗？ - 对 玛雅·汉森来了
- Is somebody there?  - Yeah, it's Maya Hansen.
以前认识的普通朋友 搞植物学的
Old botanist pal that I used to know, barely.
不会还有个
Please don't tell me that there is a
没见过我的12岁小孩在车里等着吧
12-year-old kid waiting in the car that I've never met.
他13了 当然不是 我想请你帮忙
He's 13. No, I need your help.
干嘛？为嘛现在来找？
What for? Why now?
我看过报纸了
Because I read the papers, and,
说实话 我觉得你撑不过这周
frankly, I don't think you'll last the week.
- 我会没事的 - 对不起
- I'll be fine.  - I'm sorry.
哈皮住院了
With Happy in the hospital,
- 我都不知道还会有客人来 - 确实没想到
- I didn't know we were expecting guests.  - We weren't.
- 特别是前女友! - 她不是
- And old girlfriends!  - She's not really.
不 不是 一夜情而已
No, not really. It was just one night.
- 是啊 - 你就爱这样说是吧？
- Yep.  - That's how you did it, isn't it?
那晚挺美妙的
It was a great night
- 呃 差不多了 - 是啊
- Well... you know  - Yeah.
幸好没成事 要不你得后悔死了
You have saved yourself a world of pain.
- 啥？ - 相信我
- What?  - Trust me.
我们要出城了
We're going out of town.
- 我们什么没经历过 不用出城 - 要出去
- Okay, we've been through this. Nope.  - Yep!
- 我说不去 - 马上就走
- The man says no.  - Immediately and indefinitely.
- 好主意 我们走吧 - 对不起
- Great idea. Let's go.  - I'm sorry.
这主意很糟糕 别动她的包
That's a terrible idea. Please don't touch her bags.
托尼 这样做才像正常人
Tony, this is how normal people behave.
在外面我可没法保护你 我挑衅了…
I can't protect you out there. I challenged...
- 这正常吗？ - 不好意思 那个…
- Is that normal?  - Sadly, that
是的 很正常!
Yes, this is normal!
- 非常正常 - 大兔子而已 别大惊小怪
- It's very normal.  - It's a big bunny, relax about it!
- 冷静! - 我专门送你的
- Calm down!  - I got this for you.
我知道啊
I'm aware of that.
你还没告诉我你喜不喜欢 我问了你三次…
You still haven't even told me that you liked it! I asked you three...
- 我不喜欢! - 你不喜欢？!
- I don't like it!  - You don't like it?!
我们都要出去了
We are leaving the house,
- 这有什么好争的 - 伙计们 那个
- that's not even up for discussion.  - Guys... do we umm...
- 什么？ - 那里没关系吗？
- What?  - Do we need to worry about that?
- 我来保护你 - 我先保护你的
- I got you.  - I got you first.
我都说了 咱们不能呆在这
Like I said, we can't stay here.
赶紧走! 我就来
Move! I'm right behind.
抓住她 我这就找条路
Get her, I'm going to find a way around.
别停下! 带上她 快出去 快
Stop stopping! Get her. Get outside! Go!
我的天啊 托尼
Oh my God. Tony!
先生 珮珀已经安全出去了
Sir, Miss Potts is clear of the structure.
贾维斯 我的飞行能力呢
Jarvis, where's my flight power?
正在弄呢 先生 这只是个样机
Working on it, sir. This is a prototype.
第一个
That's one.
先生 这套战衣还没有进入战斗状态
Sir, the suit is not combat-ready.
第二个
That's two.
托尼!
Tony!
先生 深吸一口气
Sir, take a deep breath.
飞行能力恢复
Flight power restored.
先生 先生
Sir. Sir!
好吧 关掉闹钟 我已经醒了
Alright, kill the alarm. I got it.
那是战衣能量
That's the emergency alert
低于5%的紧急警告
triggered by the power dropping below 5%.
下雪了？ 我们这是在哪 北部吗？
Snow? Where are we, upstate?
我们在田纳西州玫瑰山外5英里
We are 5 miles outside of Rose Hills, Tennessee.
什么？
Why?
贾维斯! 这可不是我的主意 我们在这干嘛
Jarvis! Not my idea! What are we doing here, this is
这都千里之外了 我得找到珮珀 我得…
thousands of miles away? I've gotta get Pepper, I've got to...
这是您定的飞行计划
I prepared a flight plan.
目的地设在这儿
This was the location.
谁说的 打开战衣
Who asked you? Open the suit.
我好像出故障了 先生
I think I may be malfunctioning, sir.
打开
Open Eject.
轻快多了
That's brisk!
还是呆里面舒服一点
Maybe I'll just cozy back up for a bit.
我现在得睡觉了 先生
I actually think I need to sleep now, sir.
贾维斯
Jarvis.
贾维斯？
Jarvis?
别丢下我啊 伙计
Don't leave me, buddy.
斯塔克安全服务器 正在传送所有已知设备
Stark Secure Server: Now transferring to all known receivers.
珮珀 是我
Pepper, it's me.
我要向你道歉
I've got a lot of apologies
时间不多 长话短说吧 首先
to make and not a lot of time, so first off.
我很抱歉 让你身处险境
I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
我又自私又愚蠢 保证不再有下次
That was selfish and stupid and it won't happen again.
还有 圣诞节那只兔子确实太大了 完毕
Also, it's Christmas time and the rabbit's too big. Done.
对不起
Sorry.
再提前和你说声对不起 因为我还不能回家
And I'm sorry in advance because... I can't come home yet.
我得找到那个人 你要注意安全
I need to find this guy. You gotta stay safe.
就这样了
That's all I know.
我刚在一个店门口偷了件披风
I just stole a poncho from a wooden Indian.
我们来给你整好
Let's get you comfy.
你现在开心了？
You happy now?
不许动!
Freeze!
- 不许动 - 我投降
- Don't move.  - You got me.
土豆枪不错啊
Nice potato gun.
枪筒有点长
Barrel's a little long.
枪筒长口径大 威力会减弱很多
Between that and the wide gauge, it's going to diminish your FPS.
现在你没子弹了
And now you're out of ammo.
你胸口上的是什么
What's that thing on your chest?
是个电磁铁 你应该知道啊
It's a electromagnet. You should know,
你这有一箱呢
you've got a box of them right here.
用在什么东西上？
What does it power?
我的天哪
Oh my God!
- 那个是钢铁侠吗 - 理论上我才是
- Is that Iron Man?  - Technically, I am.
理论上你已经死了
Technically, you're dead.
- 有道理 - 他怎么了
- A valid point. - What happened to him?
活着呢 我造了他 自然得照顾他
Life. I built him. I take care of him.
我会修好他的
I'll fix him.
- 就像机械师一样 - 是的
- Like a mechanic.  - Yeah.
要是我来造钢铁侠和战争机器
If I was building Iron Man and War Machine,
- 现在叫钢铁爱国者 - 更酷啊
- It's Iron Patriot now.  - That's way cooler!
不 不是的
No, it's not.
要让我来 我会加个反射…
Anyway, I would have added in the retro...
- 反射面板？ - 好让他进入隐形模式
- Retroreflective panels?  - To make him stealth mode.
- 你想要做隐形模式？ - 很酷吧？
- You want a stealth mode?  - Cool, right?
这主意真好 也许我会造个这样的
That's actually a good idea. Maybe I'll build one.
这样可不好!
Not a good idea!
你在干吗？ 你要把他手指掰断么？
What are you doing? You're going to break his finger?
他已经很痛苦了 都受伤了 别碰他
He's in pain. He's been injured. Leave him alone.
- 抱歉 - 是真抱歉么？
- Sorry.  - Are you?
不要担心 我会修好他
Don't worry about it. I'll fix it.
对了 你家都有谁？
So, uh, who's home?
我妈去餐馆了
Well, my mom already left for the diner
我爸去便利店买彩票了
and dad went to 7-11 to get scratchers.
他应该中了大奖吧 因为都走了六年了
I guess he won 'cause that was six years ago.
爸爸抛弃家庭走了很正常啊 别那么伤心
Which happens, dads leave. No need to be a pussy about it.
我需要些东西
Here's what I need:
一台笔记本电脑 一块数码手表和一部手机
A laptop, a digital watch, a cell phone,
你土豆枪里的气压传动装置
The pneumatic actuator from your bazooka over there,
一张地图 一个大弹簧 还有一个金枪鱼三明治
a map of town, a big spring, and a tunafish sandwich.
- 你给我啥好处？ - 救你 他叫什么名字？
- What's in it for me?  - Salvation. What's his name?
- 谁？ - 在学校欺负你的那个 他叫什么名字？
- Who?  - The kid that bullies you at school, what's his name?
你怎么知道的？
How'd you know that?
给你看样宝贝
I got just the thing.
这是高科技的蛐蛐罐
This is a pinata for a cricket.
逗你玩的 其实是很有威力的武器
I'm kidding. It's a very powerful weapon.
离自己脸远一点 对着别人 再按顶上按钮
Point it away from your face, press the button on top,
这样就不会有人欺负你了
It discourages bullying.
不会死人 只是个自保装置
Non-lethal, just to cover one's ass.
- 成交不成交 你说 - 成交
- Deal. Deal? What'd you say? - Deal.
- 你叫什么名字 - 哈利
- What's your name? - Harley
- 你呢 - 机械工
- And you are?  - A mechanic,
托尼
Tony.
知道我一直在想什么吗
You know what keeps going through my head?
我的三明治怎么还没来
Where's my sandwich?
斯塔克安全服务器 视网膜扫描已确认身份
Stark Secure Server. Retinal scan verified.
珮珀 是我
Pepper, it's me.
我要向你道歉
I've got a lot of apologies to make
时间不多 长话短说吧 首先
and not a lot of time, so first off.
我很抱歉 让你身处险境
I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
我又自私又愚蠢 保证不再有下次
That was selfish and stupid and it won't happen again.
你今晚为什么来我家
Why were you at the house tonight?
什么事这么重要 让你非得和托尼谈
What was so important that you had to speak to Tony?
我觉得我老板在为曼达林卖命
I think that my boss is working for the Mandarin.
如果你想继续谈这事
So if you still want to talk about it,
我建议找个安全的地方说话
I suggest we get ourselves someplace safe.
你老板在为曼达林工作 怎么会
Your boss works for the Mandarin you think,
托尼明明说你是植物学家
but Tony says you're a botanist.
那也对 我其实
That figures. What I actually am
是生物基因编码人员 负责一个40人团队
is a biological DNA coder running a team of 40
归在私费资助的智囊团名下
out of a privately-funded think tank,
不过 叫我植物学家也没问题
but sure you can call me a "Botanist".
你老板叫什么名字
This boss of yours, does he have a name?
他叫阿尔德里奇·基里安
Yeah, Aldrich Killian.
我们把房子掀了个遍 可是没找到尸体
Well we took the house down sir, but there's no sign of a body.
- 我知道了 - 没找到斯塔克
- I see.  - No Stark.
我得走了
I have to go.
大师马上就要录像了 他有一点…
The Master is about to record and he's a little...
你知道他是什么脾气
Well you know how he gets.
晚上你按原计划做 完事了电话通知我
Keep your appointment tonight and call me when it's done.
好了各位 不许说话 不许有任何眼神交流
Alright everybody. No talking and no eye contact,
除非你想脸上挨枪子儿
unless you wanna get shot in the face.
大师进来了
The Master is travelling.
那我们现在开始吧
Well then, what are we waiting for?
三明治还不错 弹簧有点生锈了
The sandwich was fair, the spring was a little rusty,
其它材料勉强可使用
the rest of the materials I'll make do.
顺便说一句 你说你妹妹有手表时
By the way, when you said your sister had a watch,
我可没想到是这么个玩意儿
I was kinda hoping for something a little more than that.
她才六岁 这表还是限量版呢
She's six! Anyway, it's limited edition.
- 能聊聊纽约的事儿吗 - 不能 别老想着这茬儿
- When can we talk about New York? - Maybe never, relax about it.
那来聊聊复仇者联盟
What about the Avengers,
- 可以吗 - 我不确定 再说吧
- can you talk about them? - I don't know. Later.
孩子 你让我静静好么
Hey kid, give me more space.
这里到底发生了什么事儿
What's the official story here? What happened?
那人叫查德·戴维斯 他以前住这附近
I guess this guy named Chad Davis, used to live roundabouts.
在军队中得过很多奖章
Won a bunch of medals in the army.
有一天 大家说他发疯了 他做了炸弹
One day, folks said he went crazy and made, you know, a bomb.
就在这儿 把自己炸飞了
Then he blew himself up right here.
- 六人丧生 对吗 - 是的
- Six people died, right? - Yes.
- 包括他自己 - 是的
- Including Chad Davis? - Yea.
这不对啊
Doesn't make sense.
你想想看 死了六人 可只有五个影子
Think about it. Six dead, only five shadows.
是的 人们说
Yeah, but people said these
有影子代表灵魂死后去了天堂
shadows are like the mark of souls gone to Heaven
而造炸弹的人
Except the bomb guy,
他进了地狱 所以没有影子
he went to Hell on account of he didn't get a shadow.
- 所以就只有五个 - 你相信这说法么
- That's why there's only five. - Do you buy that?
大家都是这么说的
That's what everyone says.
你知道这弹坑让我想起了什么吗
You know what this crater reminds me of?
我不知道 我也不在乎
I have no idea. I don't care.
纽约那个巨大的虫洞
That giant wormhole, in um, in New York.
你想到了么？
Does it remind you?
你在玩儿我么 我不想谈那件事儿
That's manipulative. I don't want to talk about it.
外星侵略者还会回来吗
Are they coming back? The aliens?
可能会 你别问了好不好
Maybe, can you stop?
记得我说过我有焦虑症吗
Remember when I told you that I have an anxiety issue?
这个话题让你很紧张吗
Does this subject make you edgy?
有一点儿吧
Yeah, a little bit.
你能不能让我喘口气儿
Can I just catch my breath for a second?
玫瑰山那边也有坏人吗
Are there bad guys in Rose Hills?
要拿塑料袋帮你呼吸吗
Do you need a plastic bag to breathe into?
- 你带了药吗 - 没有
- Do you have medication? - Nope.
- 那你现在要服药吗 - 可能得服
- Do you need to be on it? - Probably.
- 你有创伤后遗症吗 - 我并不认为我有
- Do you have PTSD? - I don't think so.
你是不是快要精神病发了
Are you going completely mental?
我可以不问 你想让我停止吗
I can stop, do you want me to stop?
我说过了叫你别缠着我问
Remember when I said to stop doing that?
我发誓 你会把我逼疯的
I swear to God, you're going to freak me out.
兄弟 你真的把我逼疯了
Ah man, you did it, didn't you?
- 你现在开心了 - 我说什么了
- You happy now? - What did I say?
嗨 等等我 等等
Hey, wait up! Wait, wait.
你到底怎么了
What the hell was that?
都是你的错 你把我逼走了
Your fault, you spazzed me out.
好了 重回正题 我们刚才说到哪儿了
Okay, back to business. Where were we?
那个死了的人有亲戚吗 他的母亲 戴维斯夫人在哪儿
The guy who died... relatives?Mom? Ms. Davis, where is she?
- 她一直没走 - 看 你总算说了句有用的
- Where she always is. - See, now you're being helpful.
抱歉 女士 这…
Sorry. Lady, this uh,
谢谢你
Thank you.
发型不错 很适合你
Nice haircut, suits you.
- 手表不错 - 是啊 还是限量版呢
- Nice watch. - Yeah, limited edition.
哦 我毫不怀疑
Oh, I don't doubt it.
晚上过得愉快
Well have a good evening.
戴维斯女士 你介意我坐下来吗
Ms. Davis, Mind if I join you?
- 坐吧 没人拦你 - 确实是
- Free country. - It sure is.
好吧
Alright.
你想从哪里开始说
Where'd you like to start?
我想告诉您 我对您儿子的事很难过
I just want to say I'm sorry about your loss.
我想知道 到底发生了什么
I want to know what you think happened.
我带来了你想要的文件 你拿了就走人
I brought your damn file. You take it and go.
这里面乱七八糟的事儿 和他没关系
Whatever was in here, he wanted no part of it.
显然 你还在等什么别的人
Clearly, you were waiting for someone else.
你约了人在这儿见面吗
Supposed to meet somebody here?
是呀
Yeah.
(塔格特·J)
戴维斯女士 你儿子没有自杀
Ms. Davis, your son didn't kill himself.
我保证 他也没杀害任何人
I guarantee you, he didn't kill anyone.
他是被人利用了
Someone used him.
- 你说什么 - 被人当作武器
- What? - As a weapon.
你不是那个给我打电话的人 是不是
You're not the person who called me after all, are you?
其实是我打了你电话
Actually, I am.
喂喂 怎么回事 这他妈是怎么回事
Hey, hey! What's all this about? what the hell's going on here?
我在逮捕嫌犯
It's called an arrest.
- 你是警长吗 - 是的女士 你是谁
- Sheriff, is it? - Yes ma'am, it is. And you are?
- 我是国土安全局的 没问题了吧 - 不 有问题
- Homeland Security. We good here? - No, we're not good.
你最好说得详细点
I need a little more information than that.
还轮不着你来质询我 警长
Well, I think it's a little above your pay grade, Sheriff.
既然这样 你怎么不去纳什维尔
Yeah, well, why don't you get on the horn to Nashville
给我办个升职？
and upgrade me?
行了 你知道吗
Alright, you know what,
我本来想耍点聪明把这事解决了 但是
I was hoping to do this the smart way, but uh,
你想玩真的 我也没意见
The fun way's always good.
警士 把这个女人
Deputy, get this woman and...
辣妹要派对么 那就来吧 我陪你
Hey hot wings, you wanna party? Come on, you and me, let's go.
- 真疯狂 - 是啊
- Crazy, huh? - Yeah.
看这个
Watch this.
是你自己找上门来的
You walked right into this one.
我泡过比你更热辣的妞
I've dated hotter chicks than you.
就这点能耐？ 廉价把戏和俗套冷笑话？
That's all you got? Cheap trick and a cheesy one-liner?
甜心 我自传可能就以那个为题写了
Sweetheart, that could be the name of my autobiography.
- 放我走! - 救命! 救命!
- Let me go! - Help me! Help me!
小子 你圣诞节想要什么礼物？
Hey kid, what would you like for Christmas?
斯塔克先生 对不起
Mr. Stark, I am so sorry.
不 不 他意思是"我要那个天杀的文件"
No, no, I think he was trying to say "I want my goddamn file."
不是你的错 孩子
It's not your fault kid.
记得欺负你的同学吗？
Remember what I told you about bullies?
感觉如何？ 聪明人都这么办事
You like that, West World? That's the thing about smart guys.
我们总能自保
We always cover our ass.
不用谢哦
You're welcome!
- 什么不用谢？ - 我可救了你的命
- For what? Did I miss something?  - Me saving your life.
首先 我先救的你 然后 还是谢谢你
A: Saved you first. B: Thanks, sort of.
最后 提个建议 帮了人也别嚷嚷好吗
And C: If you do someone a solid, don't be a yutz alright,
淡定点 不然你就掉大价了
just play it cool otherwise you come off grandiose.
你也这样么？
Unlike you?
承认吧 你需要我 我们心有灵犀
Admit it, you need me. We're connected.
我只要你回家 和你妈待一起
What I need is for you to go home, be with your mom,
管好你的嘴 守好战衣
keep your trap shut, and guard the suit.
随时保持电话联系
And stay connected to the telephone because
我一打电话你就接 好吗
if I call you better pick up. Okay?
你感受到了吗 这儿没我们事了
Can you feel that? We're done here.
挪开 不然会被车碾到 再见 小孩
Move out of the way or I'm going to run you over. Bye kid.
对不起 孩子 你做的不错
I'm sorry kid. You did good.
你还是要抛弃我么 跟我爸一样？
So now you're just going to leave me here, like my dad?
是的 等等 你想让我觉得内疚是吧
Yeah. Wait, you're guilt-tripping me, aren't you?
我好冷
I'm cold.
我看得出来 你猜我怎么看出来的？
I can tell. You know how I can tell?
因为我们心有灵犀
'Cause we're connected.
还是值得一试的
It was worth a shot.
这个并不贵 又特别漂亮 简直是百…
You get this. It's affordable. It's gorgeous. It goes with any deco...
影像怎么了
What happened to pictures?
- 这是怎么了？ - 整个洛杉矶都是
- How is this happening again? - Fine. Override to Los Angeles.
整个东海岸 卫星都沦陷了
The entire East coast.. the satellites are down.
我们接到了一个不明广播信号
We have an unauthorized broadcast
副总统先生 您可能需要看这个
Mr. Vice President, I think you should see this.
哦我的神 又来了
Oh my God, not again.
总统能看到这个吗
Is the President getting this?
总统先生
Mr. President.
还有两课要讲
Only two lessons remain.
我想在圣诞节前结束
I intend to finish this before Christmas morning.
这位是汤姆斯·理查德 好名字 工作也很出色
Meet Thomas Richards. Good strong name, good strong job.
汤姆斯是劳克斯石油公司的会计
Thomas here is an accountant for the Roxxon Oil Corporation.
我也确认他是好人
And I'm sure he's a really good guy.
我待会要爆掉他的头
I'm going to shoot him in the head,
30秒后枪杀他 等着看直播吧
live on your television, in 30 seconds.
你手机里有这部电话的号码
The number for this telephone is in your cell phone.
振奋人心是不
Exciting, isn't it?
想想就激动
Imagining how it got there.
美国人 如果你们的总统
America, if your president
30秒内打电话给我 汤姆就不用死
calls me in the next half-minute, Tom lives.
行动
Go.
他怎么黑进我手机的
How did he hack my phone?
我们不能任由恐怖分子为所欲为
We can't allow terrorists to dictate
我必须打这个电话
I have to make this call.
我强烈反对
I'd strongly advise against that.
打电话才对
This is the right thing to do.
接下来只有一课了 埃利斯总统
There's just one lesson left, President Ellis,
赶快逃难吧 和你的孩子们吻别吧
so run away and kiss your children goodbye,
因为任何东西 包括你的军队
because nothing, not your army,
包括你的钢铁战狗 都救不了你
not your red, white, and blue attack dog, can save you.
我们很快会再相见
I'll see you soon.
命令罗迪 现在就找到这个疯子
Tell Rhodes, find this lunatic right now.
先生 我们追踪了广播信号
Sir, we tracked the broadcast signal.
信号源地可能在巴基斯坦
We have a possible point of origin in Pakistan
钢铁爱国者随时待命
and the Patriot is ready to strike.
- 现在行动! - 是 长官
- Right now! - Yes, sir.
(任务执行期失踪人员)
都别动!
Don't move!
呃 等等
Uh, hang on a second.
喂
Hello.
你遇到过这么个小妞么 仔细看她时
Did you have a chick striking you and you look up and so then she
发现她由内向外散发亮橘色的光
glowing from the inside out, a kind of bright orange.
- 遇到过 你是？ - 是我 哥们
- Yeah, I've had that. Who is this? - It's me, pal.
上次我失踪时
Now last time I went missing,
没记错的话 你好像有事找我
if I remember correctly, you came looking for me.
- 你在干吗 - 聊聊天
- What are you doing? - A little talking,
和巴基斯坦人交交朋友
making friends in Pakistan.
你在干吗呢
What are you doing?
- 你的新形象是AIM设计的对吗 - 是的
- Your re-design, your big re-brand, that was AIM, right? - Yeah.
我要找颗卫星 告诉我你的登陆账号
I'm gonna find a heavy-duty comsat right now, I need your login.
和以前一样 战争机器68
Same as it's always been, WarMachine68.
密码多少
And password please?
其实我换了 你黑一次我就得改一次
Well, look, I gotta change it every time you hack in, Tony.
又不是80年代
It's not the eighties,
不流行"黑"了 报上新账户名
nobody says "Hack" Anymore, give me your login.
战争机器最酷 全大写
"WARMACHINEROX" with an X, all caps.
- 好的 - 哈哈 比钢铁爱国者顺耳多了
- Yeah okay.  - Hahah That is so much better than Iron Patriot.
很好很好 我有一个问题给你
Very nice. Very nice. I have one question for you.
你今年圣诞节想要什么
What will you like for Christmas this year?
戴维 我…
Well, David, I...
网速太慢
That ain't gonna cut it.
对不起 先生 我不知道你…
Excuse me sir, I don't know who...
妈 我得挂了 奇迹发生了
Mom, I need to call you back. Something magical is happening.
- 托尼·斯塔克在我面包车里 - 小点声
- Tony Stark is in my van. - Keep it down.
- 托尼·斯塔克在我面包车里 - 不 他不在
- Tony Stark is in my van! - No, he's not.
我就知道你还活着
I knew you were still alive!
进来 把门关上
Come on in and close the door.
- 可以恕我直言吗先生 - 说
- Wow, can I just say sir? - Yeah.
我是你的铁杆粉丝
I am your biggest fan.
先问下 这是你的车吗 有其他人要进来吗
Okay, first, is this your van or is anyone else gonna come in?
不不 就咱俩
No, no, it's just us.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
- 盖里 - 你好
- Gary. - Hi.
哦哇噢
Oh wow.
没事的 这种情况我常遇到 别紧张
Right that's fine. I get a lot of this, it's okay.
能恕我直言吗
Can I just say?
- 说 - 不知道你看出来没 但是我
- Yeah. - I don't know if you can tell but I have like
造型全向你看齐
Patterned my whole look after you.
但头发不好 又没用护发品
My hair is just a little, it's not right. Just no product in it.
嗯
Right.
我不想让你觉得尴尬
I don't want to make things awkward for you
- 对的 - 但我还要让你看 嘣!
- No. - But I do have to show you... boom!
西班牙版斯科特·拜奥
Hispanic Scott Baio?
- 哦对不起 是我吗 - 是的
- Oh, I'm sorry, is that me? - Yeah.
我让人照着我做的一个公仔刺的
It's... I mean. I had them do it off a doll that I made,
不像用照片做参考 所以有点…
so it's not like it's off a picture. So it's a little bit-
盖里 现在听我说
Gary, for a moment, listen to me here.
我不想打击你
I don't want to clip your wings here.
但咱俩确实兴奋过头了
We're both a little over-excited.
我有事儿办 在追查坏人 但同时
I have an issue. I'm chasing bad guys, trying to
我要先从机密数据库里弄点资料
grapple with something from some hard-crypt data files.
可是信号不好
I don't have enough juice.
请你去车顶 调一下网络
I need you to jump on the roof, recalibrate the ISDNs.
提速40%
Pump it up by about 40%.
- 明白啦 - 好的 这是交你的任务
- Got it.  - Alright, it's a mission.
是
Yeah.
托尼需要盖里
Tony needs Gary.
盖里也需要托尼
And Gary needs Tony.
不要声张
Be quiet about it.
去吧
Go.
你生命中最意义非凡的一刻是什么
What would you regard as the defining moment of your life?
我想那一定是
Well uh, I think that would be
我决定不再受伤痛折磨的那一刻
the day I decided not to let my injury beat me.
- 你能对着镜头说出你的名字吗 - 艾伦·布兰特
- Can you please state your name for the camera? - Ellen Brant.
我们将对你进行周期性注射
Okay, so, the injections are administered periodically.
禁止药物上瘾
Addiction will not be tolerated and
控制不住药瘾的将离开项目
those who cannot regulate will be cut from the program.
曾经是边缘人 残疾人
Once misfits, cripples...
但现在起 你们会是人类进化的优胜者
you are the next iteration of human evolution.
大家伙儿 在开始前 我保证
Hi everybody. Before we start, I promise you,
当你回顾人生
looking back at your life there will be
作为第一批实验人选
nothing as bitter as the memory of
其中的艰苦和荣耀都会让你永生难忘
that glorious risk that you prudently elected to forego.
你们今天很光荣 开始吧
Today is your glory. Let's begin!
我们得赶紧出去 赶紧出去
We gotta get out of here! Gotta get out of here!
带他们出去 带他们出去
Get 'em out! Get 'em out of here!
不是炸弹的炸弹 原来就是人肉炮弹
A bomb is not a bomb when it's a misfire.
这东西不是每次都奏效 对吧 老兄
This stuff doesn't always work, right, pal?
有缺陷 但你找到了买家 不是吗
It's faulty, but you found a buyer, didn't ya?
卖给了曼达林
Sold it to the Mandarin.
- 发生了什么 - 有趣的事情
- What happened?  - Fun fact.
为纳粹造火箭前
Before he built rockets for the Nazis.
这位理想主义者 沃纳·冯·布劳恩
The idealistic Werner von Braun
梦想过太空旅行
dreamed of space travel.
这是他的幻想
He stargazed.
知道第一枚V2火箭击中伦敦时他说了什么吗
You know what he said when the first V2 hit London?
火箭表现完美无瑕
The rocket performed perfectly.
可惜落在了错误的星球
It just landed on the wrong planet.
看吧 我们一开始很天真 只是纯粹的科学
See, we all begin wide-eyed... "Pure science".
接着自我开始膨胀 变得偏执
Then the ego steps in, the obsession
当你回头看时 已经走得太远了
And when you look up, you're a long way from shore.
别太苛责自己
You can't be too hard on yourself,
玛雅 是智囊团利用了你的研究成果
Maya. I mean you gave your research to a think tank.
但基里安的智囊团和军方本就是合作关系
Yeah, but Killian built that think tank on military contracts.
我们以前也这样
That's exactly what we used to do.
别苛求自己了
So don't judge yourself.
谢谢你 珮珀
Thank you, Pepper.
真的很感谢
I really appreciate that.
嗨 晚上好
Hi, good evening.
- 晚上好 - 进来吧
- Good evening. - Come on in.
玛雅 快跑
Maya, run!
嗨 珮珀
Hi Pepper.
想不想告诉我
So you want to tell me
昨晚为什么去斯塔克家
why you were at Stark's manison last night?
我想要解决问题 我不知道
I'm trying to fix this thing. I didn't
你跟老大要把那里炸掉
know you and the Master were gonna blow the place up.
我明白了 你想救斯塔克
Oh I see, so you were trying to save Stark
哪怕他威胁我们
when he threatened us.
我告诉过你 我们可以利用他
I told you, Killian, we can use him.
珮珀 珮珀 珮珀
Pepper, Pepper, Pepper
如果明年要推新品就需要斯塔克
Look if we want to launch product next year, I need Stark.
他不过是缺少动机 现在他有了
He just lacked a decent incentive. Now he has one.
这里是蓝0支援组
This is Support Team Blue 0,
已发送疑似曼达林视频信号来源地坐标
sending coordinates for suspected Mandarin broadcast point of origin.
收到
Copy.
都别动
Nobody move!
蓝0队 除非曼达林下次袭击美国
Support Blue 0, unless the Mandarin's next attack on the U.S.
要用到廉价运动服 不然我认为你们又搞砸了
involves cheaply-made sportswear, I think you messed up again.
你们自由了 看来之前不是自由身 是的女士
Yes, you're free, if you weren't before. Yes ma'am.
钢铁爱国者为您服务
Iron Patriot on the job, happy to help,no
不用谢 这是我应该做的
need to thank me, it's my pleasure.
赛文 我拿到了爱国者战衣
Savin, I've acquired the Patriot armor.
你想要这件战衣吗
You want this suit?
除非你把我的尸体从里面拖出来
You're going to have to pry my cold, dead body out of it.
我也是这么想的 上校
That's the plan, Colonel.
哈利 告诉我怎么样了 说详细点
Harley, tell me what is happening, give me a full report.
我还在吃糖
Yeah, I'm still eating that candy,
想让我继续吃吗
do you want me to keep eating it?
你吃了多少
How much did you have?
两三碗吧
Two or three bowls.
- 你看得清东西吗 - 勉强可以
- Can you still see straight?  - Sort of.
那说明你没事 把电话给贾维斯
That means you're fine, give me Jarvis.
贾维斯 怎么样了
Jarvis, how are we?
先生 一切正常 不过前句能好好说话
It's totally fine sir. I seem to do quite well for a stretch and
后句再说就会出错
then at the end of the sentence I say the wrong cranberry.
主人 你说的对
And sir, you were right.
在对AIM的卫星接收设备进行分析后
Once I factored in available AIM downlink facilities
我成功定位了曼达林视频的来源地
I was able to pinpoint the Mandarin's broadcast signal.
在哪？ 远东 欧洲
What're we talkin'? The Far East, Europe,
北非 伊朗 巴基斯坦 叙利亚 到底在哪儿
North Africa, Iran, Pakistan, Syria, where is it?
其实在迈阿密
Actually, sir, it's in Miami.
好了 孩子
Okay, kid, I'm going to
我要教你重启贾维斯的语音驱动
have to walk you through rebooting Jarvis's speech drive,
但不是现在
but not right now.
哈利 他到底在哪儿
Harley, where is he really?
看着屏幕 告诉我他在哪儿
Just look on the screen and tell me where it is.
确实在佛罗里达州的迈阿密
Um...it does say Miami, Florida.
好 先说重要的 我需要战衣
Okay, first things first, I need the armor.
它现在什么状态
Where are we at with it?
还没充电
Uh, it's not charging.
主人 它其实正在充电
Actually, sir, it is charging,
但是电源好像有问题
but the power source is questionable.
可能无法让42代恢复活力
It may not succeed in revitalizing the Mark 42.
电源有什么问题
What's questionable about electricity?
这是我的战衣 我不能 我不会
Alright, it's my suit and I can't... I'm not gonna...
- 哦天呐 又来了 - 托尼
- Oh God, not again.  - Tony
你又发病了吗 我根本没提纽约
Are you having another attack? I didn't even mention New York.
对 可你刚刚又说了这个词
Right, and then you just said it,
说没提的时候你又说了一遍
by name, while denying having said it.
好吧
Okay, um, uh.
天哪 我该怎么办
Oh God, what am I gonna do?
呼吸 深呼吸就好
Just breathe, really just breathe.
- 你是个机械师 对吗 - 对啊
- You're a mechanic, right?  - Right.
- 你这么说的对吧 - 是 我说过
- You said so.  - Yes, I did.
你为什么不造点东西呢
What don't you just build something?
好主意
Okay.
谢谢你 孩子
Thanks, kid.
(佛罗里达州 迈阿密)
怎么这么热 说过要你把空调打到20度
Why is it so hot in here? I told you to put it at 68.
又怪我了 告诉你吧 甜心
My fault again. Let me tell you something sweetheart,
你不能随便使唤…
I am not your personal...
真臭 20分钟内我是不会再去的
I wouldn't go in there for twenty minutes!
- 你们两个谁是瓦内莎 - 是我
- Now, which one of you is Vanessa?  - That's me.
啊 小莎莎
Ah, Nessie.
知道吗 幸运饼不是中国产的
Did you know that fortune cookies aren't even Chinese?
这边有个人
There's some guy over here.
- 是美国人用日本配方做的 - 嘿
- They're made by Americans, based on the Japanese recipes.  - Hey!
天哪 天哪
Bloody hell. Bloody hell.
- 别动 - 我不动
- Don't move.  - I am not moving.
想要什么就拿吧 这些枪都是假的
If you want something, take it, although the guns are all fake
因为那些混蛋不敢给我真枪
because those wankers wouldn't trust me with the real ones.
- 什么 - 那要不把这俩妞带走？
- What?  - Hey, do you fancy either of the birds?
够了 你不是曼达林 真的在哪儿
Heard enough. You're not him, the Mandarin, the real guy, where?
- 曼达林在哪儿 他在哪儿 - 他在这儿 他在这儿
- Where's the Mandarin? Where is he?  - He's here. He's here.
但他又不在这儿
But he's not here.
- 他在这儿但又不在这儿 - 你什么意思
- He's here but he's not here.  - What do you mean?
这很复杂 很复杂的 你知道吗
It's complicated, hey, it's complicated, alright?
- 是吗 - 挺复杂
- It is?  - It's complicated.
那就简单点说 女人都下床 出去
Uncomplicate it. Ladies out, get out of the bed,
到厕所去
get in the bathroom.
坐下
Sit.
我叫特雷弗 特雷弗·斯莱特利
My name is Trevor, Trevor Slattery.
你干什么的
What are you?
你是诱饵还是替身
What're you, a decoy? You're a double, right?
什么 不是替身 绝对不是
What? No. An understudy? Absolutely not.
请别伤害我 我只是个演员
Don't hurt me please! I'm an actor.
让你多活一分钟 把话说清楚
You got a minute to live, fill it with words.
这是个角色而已 "曼达林"不是真的
It's just a role. "The Mandarin", see, it's not real.
那你怎么到这来的 特雷弗
Then how did you get here, Trevor?
呃 我喜欢嗑点那啥
Um, well, uh, I have a little problem with, um, substances,
然后就做了些坏事 没错
and I ended up doing things... no two ways about it
- 当街做了些坏事 - 然后呢
- In the street that a man shouldn't do.  - Next!
然后他们找到了我
Then, they approached me
跟我说了角色 他们也知道我有毒瘾
about the role and they knew about the drugs.
那是要帮你戒毒咯？
What'd they say they'd get you off them?
说会给我更多毒品
Said they'd give me more.
他们给我很多东西 比如这座宫殿
They gave me things. They gave me this palace.
还给我整了容 反正就是给我东西吧
They gave me plastic surgery. They gave me things.
你难道睡着了？
Did you just nod off?
没 还有艘美翻了的快艇 最主要的原因是他需要有人
No, the lovely speedboat! And the thing was, he needed someone.
来承担这些"意外爆炸事件"的责任
To take credit for some "Accidental explosions".
他？
"He"?
- 基里安么？ - 对 基里安
- Killian?  - Killian.
- 他创造了你？ - 嗯他创造了我
- He created you? - He created me.
- 恐吓也是他们炮制的 - 对头
- Custom-made terror threat.  - Yes!
是的 智囊团设计了这出好戏
Yes, his think tank thinked it up,
设计出变态连环杀人犯
the pathology of the serial killer.
塑造一个极恶份子形象
The manipulation of Western iconography.
"准备好再上一课了么？" 之类之类的
"Ready for another lesson?" Blah blah blah.
当然了 是我的表演
Of course, it was my performance
让曼达林这角色形象饱满
that brought the Mandarin to life.
你的表演？ 真杀了人也是表演？
Your performance? Where people die?
不不 你看看周围 戏服 绿屏
No, no, look around you, costumes, green screen.
说实话 我一般没在现场
Honestly, I wasn't on location for half this stuff,
到了现场 就都是电影特效了 亲
and when I was, movie magic, love.
真是不好意思 我有个好友
I'm sorry but I got a best
还在医院里昏迷不醒 性命堪忧
friend who's in a coma and he might not wake up.
都是你扮的曼达林惹的好事
So you're going to have to answer for that.
你玩完了 伙计
You're still going down, pal.
特雷弗 你和他说了些什么？
Okay, Trevor, what'd you tell him?
- 我啥也没说 - 什么都没说？
- I didn't tell him anything.  - Nothing?
- 没有 - 你应该按紧急按钮的
- No.  - You should have pressed the panic button.
确实紧急 但我自己不是解决了么
Well I panicked, but then I handled it.
感觉时光倒流了 对吧？
Just like old times, huh?
是啊 这回还加上了扎带 爽得很
Oh yeah, with zip-ties. It's a ball.
不是我的主意
It wasn't my idea.
当年 你拿了基里安的名片
Okay, so you took Killian's card
我接受了他的钱
I took his money.
如今 13年后 你被他关起来了
And here you are 13 years later in a dungeon.
- 并不是 - 才怪
- No.  - Yeah.
- 不是的 被关的是你 我来去自如 - 好吧
- No, you're in a dungeon. I'm free to go. - Yeah...
托尼 经历这么多后 我快成功了
A lot's happened Tony, and I'm close.
终极改造基本稳定了
Extremis is pratically stable.
根本不稳定
I'm telling you it isn't.
人们在街上被炸飞
I saw him on the street, people are going 'bang',
鲜血染红了墙 玛雅 你自欺欺人
they're painting the walls. Maya, you're kidding yourself.
那帮我改好它啊
Then help me fix it.
这是我写的？
Did I do that?
- 是的 - 我记得那晚 但不记得次日早上
- Yes.  - I remember the night, not the morning.
你一直在找这个的答案么？
Is this what you've been chasing around?
- 你不记得了？ - 我帮不了你
- You don't remember?  - I can't help you.
以前的你 有道德操守有抱负
You used to have a moral psychology. You used to have ideals.
一心想要帮人 但现在 看看你
Wanted to help people, now look at you.
幸运的是 每天躺我身边陪我醒来的人
I get to wake up every morning with someone who...
还有灵魂
still has a soul.
把我弄出去吧
Get me out of here.
拜托了
Come on.
知道吗 我老爸以前总和我说
You know what my old man used to say to me?
这么一句
One of his favorite of many sayings.
"早起的鸟儿有虫吃 第二只老鼠才能得到奶酪"
"The early bird gets the worm, the second mouse gets the cheese".
你是不是因为瑞士的事生气
You're not still pissed about the Switzerland thing, are you?
我怎么会生你的气呢 托尼
How can I be pissed at you, Tony?
我专门来谢你的 你给了我最棒的礼物
I'm here to thank you. You've given me the greatest gift
比啥礼物都好
that anybody's ever given me.
就是绝望
Desperation.
当初在瑞士
If you think back to Switzerland,
你怎么说的 你说跟我在房顶见 是吧？
you said you'd meet me on the rooftop, right?
等了20分钟后 我还觉得你会来
Well for the first 20 minutes, I actually thought you'd show up.
然后又一个小时过去 我…
For the next hour, I uhh...
我想过跨出那一步
Well I considered taking that one step
直接空降大厅 懂我意思吧
shortcut to the lobby, if you know I mean.
说实话 我还在想
Honestly, I'm still trying to
第一只老鼠为啥吃不到奶酪
figure out what happened to the first mouse.
但当我俯瞰城市 没人知道我在那里
But as I looked out over that city, nobody knew I was there,
没人能看到我 甚至都没人在看
nobody could see me, no one was even looking.
一个念头油然而生 并伴随了我这么些年
I had a thought that would guide me for years to come.
隐匿自己
Anonymity, Tony.
多亏了你 从那以后我就把它当成行事准则
Thanks to you, it's been my mantra ever since, right?
只隐藏在背后当推手
You simply rule from behind the scenes.
因为一旦你给邪恶安上一张脸
Because the second you give evil a face
比如本拉登 卡扎菲 曼达林
Bin Laden, Gaddafi, The Mandarin
都是众矢之的
You hand the people a target.
而你不是
You're something else.
你见过他了吧
You have met him, I assume?
是的 混世大王
Yeah, Sir Lawrence Oblivion.
我知道他偶尔有些夸张
I know he's a little over the top sometimes...
这又不是我的错
it's not entirely my fault.
舞台演员都有点夸张
He has a tend...he's a stage actor.
据说他演李尔王在克罗伊登很卖座 谁知道哪儿呢
They say his Lear was the toast of Croydon, wherever that is.
总之 自从
Anyway, the point is ever since
雷神都手持锤子从天而降了
that big dude with the hammer fell out of the sky.
保持低调实在是没必要
Subtlety's kinda had its day.
你接下来有什么打算？
What's next for you in your world?
我是想报答你
Well, I wanted to repay you
回赠谢礼 回应你当年善意的礼物
the same gift you so graciously imparted to me.
绝望
Desperation.
这是现场直播的 能看出来么
Now, this is live. I'm not sure if you can tell.
现在她的身体在决定
But at this moment the body is trying to decide
是否接受终极改造
whether to accept Extremis or just give up.
如果不接受
And if it gives up,
不得不说 爆炸会特别壮观
I have to say the detonation is quite spectactular.
但在那之前 确实会很疼很疼
But until that point, it's really just a lot of pain.
我们还没谈工资的事呢
We haven't even talked salary yet.
你想要什么福利？
What kind of perk package are you thinking of?
放开他
Let him go.
等等 等一下
Hold on, hold on.
- 玛雅 - 我说了放开他
- Maya.  - I said let him go!
你这是干什么？
What are you doing?
1200毫升 只要一半我就死定了
1200ccs, a dose half of this size and I'm dead.
她这不是考验我的暴脾气么
It's times like this my temper is tested somewhat.
玛雅 注射器给我
Maya, give me the injector.
基里安 要是我死了 你的士兵们怎么办？
If I die Killian, what happens to your soldiers?
你的产品怎么办？
What happens to your product?
不能这么干 好吧？
We're not doing this, okay?
你怎么办？ 你要是过热了怎么办？
What happens to you? What happens if you go too hot?
好消息 一个高层职位刚空了出来
The good news is, a high level position has just been vacated.
- 你这个疯子 - 不是的 我是个有远见的人
- You're a maniac.  - No, I'm a visionary.
但是我掌控着一个疯子 他今晚即将登台
But I do own a maniac, and he takes the stage tonight.
一旦把钢铁爱国者安插进飞机
Once we get the Iron Patriot installed,
九到十分钟就可以把事情解决
it'll take me nine to ten minutes for a take down.
很好嘛
That's great.
但还有人在战衣里呢
The last time I looked there was somebody inside of it.
下午好 先生们
Afternoon, gentlemen.
你好 上校
Hello, Colonel.
让开
Step aside.
我们会把你弄出来的 别担心
We'll get you out of there, don't worry.
这样会破坏战衣
You'll damage the armor.
是的 但你能修好 对吧？
Yes, I will, but you can fix it, right?
我会带着这套战衣回基地
I'm going to take the suit up to base camp,
把珮珀带上跟我走
and I want Potts with me.
她还在第二阶段
She's still in Phase 2.
你没变聋吧 嗯？
You're not going deaf, are ya?
轻拿轻放 那可是限量版
Careful there. It's a limited edition.
嘿 我说马尾巴
Hey, uh, ponytail express.
- 田纳西和迈阿密的距离有多少 - 832英里
- What is the mileage count between Tennessee and Miami?  - 832 miles.
很好
Very nice.
我就这么厉害
I'm good like that.
- 你能不让它叫唤吗 - 弄坏了就得赔
- Can you, uh, stop that? - Break it you bought it.
- 那我赔吧 - 好吧 那不是我的东西
- I think I bought it.  - Okay, that wasn't mine to give away.
是我朋友妹妹的
That belongs to my friend's sister,
所以我最先会干掉你
and that's why I'm gonna kill you first.
- 你打算怎么做 - 你会知道的
- What're ya gonna do to me?  - You'll see.
你被绑在床上呢
You're zip-tied to a bed.
看招
This.
再一发
That.
你要出来了吗
Are you comin' out?
别打开 别打开 别开
Do not open. Do not open. Don't open.
别开 别 好吧 那来吧
Don't open. Don't... Alright, let's go.
你还喷火 成吧
You breathe fire? Okay.
美好的一天啊 赛文
It's a glorious day, Savin.
明天这个时候
This time tomorrow,
我将一手掌握西方国家最有权利的领导人
I'll have the West's most powerful leader in one hand,
另一手则控制最令人畏惧的恐怖分子
and the world's most feared terrorist in the other.
我将拥有恐怖战争
I'll own the War on Terror,
为你和你的兄弟姊妹创造需求 提供供给
creates supply and demand for you and your brothers and sisters.
相信我 你将倒在自己的血泊中
Trust me. You're going in a puddle of blood on the ground
倒数5 4 3 快来啊 2
in 5, 4, 3. Come on! 2.
我们到底怎么摊上这货的
How did we get this shit?
好吧 我是在给你逃跑的机会
Alright, I'm going to give you a chance to escape,
放下你的武器
put down your weapons,
再把自己绑在椅子上 我就不杀你们
tie yourselves into those chairs. I'll let you live.
倒数5 4 砰
In 5, 4. Ban!
你俩应该早闪开的 你们真的该闪人了
You should be gone by now. You should have already been gone.
我真是被你吓坏了
I'm just beyond terrified.
就来了
Here it comes.
3 4
3, 4.
- 闭嘴 - 54321
- Shut up. - 54321.
早告诉你了
Told you.
剩下的呢
Where's the rest?
其实我讨厌在这里工作 他们都太奇怪了
Honestly, I hate working here. They are so weird.
来得还不算太晚
Better late than never.
这次不要 别打脸
Not this time. Not the face.
呼 能回来真好 你好啊
Phew, it's good to be back. Hello, by the way.
您好 先生
Oh, hello sir.
所有人员注意 斯塔克已脱逃 正在基地某处
All personnel, Stark is loose and somewhere in the compound.
再说一次 斯塔克已脱逃 正在基地某处
Repeat. Stark is loose and somewhere in the compound.
来吧 出发
Ah. Let's go
哦 糟糕
Ah, crap.
- 托尼 - 罗迪 是你在飞那战衣么
- Tony.  - Rudy, tell me that was you in the suit.
不是 你拿到你的了？
No, you got yours?
嗯 差不多吧 尽快去主屋
Uh, um, kind of. Main house as fast as you can.
想让你见一个人
Somebody I'd like you to meet.
你 你 你 闪开 出去
You, you, you. Move! Get out!
屋子安全了 我在看着曼达林
The room is secure. I have eyes on the Mandarin.
看这是啥 赢家拿着的球拍
What's this? I have winner's.
你这演的是谁啊
What've you come as?
敢动一下 我就打烂你的脸
You make a move and I'll break your face.
我没想过会有人伤亡 他们骗了我
I never thought people had been hurt. They lied to me.
这货竟然是曼达林？
This is the Mandarin?
我懂你意思 这 确实挺丢人的
I know, it's, it's embarrassing.
嘿 我叫特雷弗 特雷弗·斯莱特利
Hi, I'm Trevor, Trevor Slattery.
我真人比电视里矮小些 大家都这么说
I know I'm shorter in person, a bit small, everyone says that but, uh
嘿 如果你是来逮捕我的 我倒是有几个角色想尝试
Hey, if you're here to arrest me, there are some people who I'd like to roll on.
情况是这样的 梅姨
Here's how it works, Meryl Streep.
你告诉他珮珀在哪里 他就会停下那事儿
You tell him where Pepper is and he'll stop doing it.
啥事儿 嗷 我懂了 嗷 疼死了 我懂了 我懂了
Doing what? Oh, I get it! Ow! That hurt! I get it! I get it!
我不知道啥珮珀 但我清楚其他计划
I do not know about any Pepper, but I know about the plans.
- 说 - 你知道他们拿我的战衣干什么吗？
- Spill.  - Do you know what they did to my suit?
什么 不 不过我知道海边会发生什么
What?  No.  But I do know what's happening off the coast.
有关一个 嗯 一条大船 我可以带你过去哦
Something to do with uh... A big boat. I can take you there.
托尼 我对上帝发誓 我要开了这家伙的脑瓜
Tony, I swear to God, I'm going to blow his face off.
哦 可能还涉及副总统
Oh this next bit may include the Vice President as well.
- 这个重要吗 - 有一点吧
- Is that, is that important?  - Somewhat.
是啊 就一点儿呢
Yeah, a little bit.
- 然后呢 - 我们怎么办
- So?  - Uh, what are we gonna do?
我们没有任何交通工具
We don't have any transport.
嘿 林戈 你刚才是不是提到了什么很炫的快艇
Hey, Ringo, didn't you say something about a "Lovely speedboat"?
他地点没说错的话 再过20分钟就能见到珮珀
If he's right about the location, we are 20 minutes from where Pepper is.
但也得搞明白副总统的事 对不
But we also have to figure out this Vice President thing, right?
我正纳闷我在给谁打电话呢
I wonder who I'm calling right now.
- 哦 是给副总统 - 谢谢
- Oh, that's the Vice President.  - Thanks.
- 你好 - 先生 我是托尼·斯塔克
- Hello.  - Sir, this is Tony Stark.
欢迎回到活人世界
Welcome back to the land of the living.
我们确信 您会卷入曼达林的阴谋之中
We believe you're about to be drawn into the Mandarin campaign,
所以会尽快送您到安全地方
and we've got to get you somewhere safe as soon as possible.
斯塔克先生 我马上要去吃蜂蜜烤火腿了
Mr. Stark, I'm about to eat honey roast ham
周围全是局里最好的探员
surrounded by the agency's finest.
而总统和罗迪上校一起 在空军一号机上
And the President is safe on Air Force One with Colonel Rhodes.
我们无需担心
I think we're good here.
长官 我就是罗迪上校
Sir, this is Colonel Rhodes.
他们把钢铁爱国者当特洛伊木马
They're using the Iron Patriot as a Trojan horse.
想除掉总统
They're gonna take out the President somehow.
我们要马上警告空军一号
We have to immediately alert that plane.
好吧 我这就去 我会让安全局锁定位置的
Okay, I'm on it. I'll have security lock it down.
如果需要 F22机半分钟内就能起飞
If need be, they can have F22s in the air in 30 seconds.
罗迪 斯塔克结束通话
Rhodes and Stark out.
一切都好吗 先生
Everything okay, sir?
都好
Couldn't be better.
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, baby.
罗迪上校 看见你能赶来真好
Colonel Rhodes. Glad to see you could make it, son.
我立刻就觉得安全多了
I feel safer already.
我们得做个决定 从总统和珮珀里选一个
We gotta make a decision. We can either save the President or Pepper.
我们救不了俩
We can't do both.
先生 我收到马里布港那边最新消息
Sir, I have an update from Malibu.
起重机终于到了
The cranes have finally arrived
正在掀开地下室的房顶
and the cellar doors are being cleared as we speak.
那我正在穿的战衣怎么样了
And what about the suit I'm wearing?
机身已经充电至92%
The armor is now at 92%.
只能凑合上了
That's gonna have to do.
哦 他来了 他来了 快给我照一张
Oh, here he comes, here he comes, get a quick picture.
有事吗 上校
Everything all right, Colonel?
很荣幸见到你 总统先生
It is an honor, Mr. President.
你要是想杀我 就赶紧动手吧
If you're gonna do it, do it.
喔 冷静点儿 先生
Woh. Cool your boots, Sir.
曼达林可不是这么做事的
That's not how the Mandarin works.
长官 空军一号遇袭
Sir. Air Force One's been compromised.
内部枪击 气温上涨
Internal shots, temperature spikes.
立刻给我影像
Get me eyes on it now.
视频正在传送 长官
Image coming through now, sir.
那是罗迪吗
Was that Rhodes?
总统在哪儿 快说
The President. Now!
他不在这儿了
He's not here.
去喷射气流找吧
Try the jet stream.
说到这个 钓鱼去吧
Speaking of which, go fish!
从那儿闪开 你个混蛋
Walk away from that, you son of a bitch.
- 天上有几个 - 13个 先生
- How many in the air?  - Thirteen, sir.
- 我能扛几个 - 4个 先生
- How many can I carry?  - Four, sir.
别乱动 别动 放松 你叫什么 希瑟
Slow down, slow down. Relax, what's your name? Heather.
听我说 看到那人了吗？
Listen to me, see that guy?
我会从他边上飞过去
I'm gonna swing by him
你趁机抓住他
and you're just gonna grab him.
你懂了吗？
You got it?
我会电麻你的手臂
I will electrify your arm,
你就没法松开手了
you won't be able to open your hand.
希瑟 你能做到的
You can do this, Heather.
很容易对吧 还剩十一个人
Easy, see? Eleven more to go.
记得猴子手拉手的游戏吗？
Remember that game called Barrel of Monkeys?
我们来模仿它
That's what we're going to do.
只不过是在一万八千英尺的空中
18,000 feet.
大家加油 抓住周围的人
Come on, people! Everybody, grab your monkey!
真棒 还有一万英尺
Nice! 10,000 feet.
- 还有六千英尺 - 加把劲
- 6,000 feet. - Come on, people.
加油 加油 加油
Come on, come on, come on
- 好的! - 还有一千尺
- Yeah! - 1000 feet.
四百英尺 两百英尺 主人
400 feet. 200 feet, sir.
真是只淘气的猴子 抓住他
It's a tricky monkey, let's get him.
嗨
Hello.
大伙都干得不错
Nice work guys. Excellent.
我们很有默契 棒极了
Good team effort all around. Go us.
好了 贾维斯 活儿还没干完
Alright, Jarvis, but it's only half done,
珮珀还等…
we still gotta get Pepp...
那玩意儿从哪冒出来的
That came out of nowhere.
老兄 我想听点好消息
Gimme some good news man.
- 他们都安全了 - 上帝保佑
- I think they all made it. - Thank God.
是啊 但我没救到总统
Yeah, but I missed the President.
你穿着战衣还救不到总统
You couldn't save the President with the suit,
怎么指望不穿它能救珮珀
how are you gonna save Pepper without nothing?
贾维斯 是时候了吗？
Uh, say Jarvis, is it that time?
执行"机器人派对"命令吗 主人？
The "House party" Protocol, sir?
对
Correct.
嗨
Hi.
你以为他会帮你么 他不会的
You think he's gonna help you... he won't.
抓你来不只是为了刺激托尼·斯塔克
Having you here is not just to motivate Tony Stark,
挺难以启齿的
it's actually more embarrassing than that.
- 把你抓来做 呃 - 战利品
- You're here as my, um - Trophy.
晚上好 先生
Good evening, sir.
总统先生 欢迎登船
Welcome aboard, Mr. President.
听说过大象坟场吗
You ever heard of an elephant graveyard?
两年前的事就是说的这艘船
Well, two years ago, the elephant in the room was this scow.
这是劳克斯石油公司的船
This is the Roxxon Norco.
你该记得它曾在彭萨科拉附近
Of course you remember when she
泄漏了一亿加仑石油
spilled 100 million gallons of crude off Pensacola.
托你的福 没人受法律制裁
Thanks to you, not one fat cat saw a day in court.
你到底想干什么？
What do you want from me?
先生 我什么也不做
Uh, nothing, sir.
我只是在电视上要一个好理由来杀你
I just needed a reason to kill you that would play well on TV.
因为 我已经在向前看
You see, I've moved on.
我找了一个新的政治傀儡
I've found myself a new political patron, and
明天这个时候 他就接替你了
At this time tomorrow, he'll have your job.
把他绑起来
String him up.
快来
Come on.
你该不会吓坏吧？
You're not gonna freak out on me, right?
我希望不会
I hope not.
噢 天哪
Oh my God.
他被吊在油罐上方
He's strung up over the oil tank,
他们要把他烧死
they're gonna light him up, man.
维京式的葬礼
Viking funeral.
- 公开处决 - 是的 被油烧死
- Public execution.  - Yeah, death by oil.
转播即将开始 各就各位
Broadcast will commence shortly. Take final positions.
很好
Okay, that's good.
现在调出摄像头A至E
Now give me cameras A
来一次完整的彩排
through E and we'll do a full tech rehearsal.
枪就位了吗？
Is your gun up?
是的 我该干嘛？
Yup, what do I do?
看好我六点钟方向 注意高处 别打到我的背
Stay on my six, cover high, and don't shoot me in the back.
身后 高处 不打背 知道了
Six, high, back. Alright.
看到了吗 我搞定了
You see that? Nailed it.
是的 你的确 打碎了蛮多玻璃
Yeah, you really killed the glass.
我瞄准的是灯泡
I was aiming for the bulb?
但这么远根本打不到
You can't hit a bulb from this distance.
我没子弹了 你还有弹夹吗？
I'm out. Gimme, gimme, you got an extra magazine?
不通用
They're not universal, Tony.
我知道 我是做这些的 给我个弹夹
I know what I'm doing, I make this stuff. Gimme another one.
和你的枪不配套
I don't have one that fits that gun.
你有五个弹夹
You've got like five of them.
好 我接下来要勘查情况了 准备好
Alright, here's what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna spot. Ready?
你看到了什么
What'd you see?
太快了 什么都没看到 再来一次
Too fast, nothing. Here we go.
三男一女 都佩枪
Three guys, one girl, all armed.
天哪 我真需要些武器
God, I'd kill for some armor right now.
- 说得对 我们需要后援 - 是的 要很多
- You're right, we need backup. - Yeah, much.
猜猜怎么着
You know what?
- 那是？ - 是的
- Is that?  - Yep.
- 那些是？ - 是的
- Are those? - Yeah.
圣诞快乐 老伙计
Merry Christmas, buddy.
贾维斯 瞄准"终极改造"体的热源
Jarvis, target Extremis heat signatures.
全部清除
Disable with extreme prejudice.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
你在等什么 圣诞到了
What are you waiting for? It's Christmas.
带他们下地狱吧
Take 'em to church.
贾维斯 让伊格尔撑住它
Jarvis, get Igor to steady this thing.
这是你的闲暇爱好喽？
This is how you've been managing your downtime, huh?
谁都有爱好嘛
Everybody needs a hobby.
碎心者 去帮帮红鳄龟吧
Heartbreaker? Help Red Snapper out, will ya?
真准时
Nice timing.
好的 太酷了 给我套战衣怎么样
Oh yeah, that's awesome. Give me a suit, okay?
真抱歉 他们是量身定做的
Oh, I'm sorry. They're only coded to me.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
我会掩护你的
I got you covered.
- 晚上好上校 能载你一程吗？ - 一点也不好笑
- Good evening, Colonel. Can I give you a lift?  - Very funny.
- 先生 我已经找到了珮珀小姐 - 是时候了
- Sir, I've located Miss Potts. - About time.
停 快把它放下来 放下来
Stop, put it down, put it down, put it down.
这就是你和我前女友来往的后果
See what happens when you hang out with my ex-girlfriends?
你真是个混蛋
You're such a jerk.
行 我们晚饭再讨论
Yup, we'll talk about it at dinner.
来 宝贝再近一点
Come on, a little more, baby.
这家伙烦到你了吗？
Is this guy bothering you?
别起来
Don't get up!
这儿热吗？
Is it hot there?
堵吗 感觉这里堵着吗？
Stuck? Feel a little stuck?
就像小乌龟 在壳里被活活烤着？
Like a little turtle, cooking in his little turtle suit?
托尼
Tony
她在看着
She's watching.
你最好闭上眼
I think you should close your eyes.
闭上眼
Close your eyes.
闭上眼 你不会想看的
Close your eyes. You don't want to see this.
你休息一会吧
Yeah, you take a minute.
贾维斯 现在就给我一套战衣
Jarvis, give me a suit right now!
快点
Aw, come on!
总统先生 坚持住 我就来了
Mr. President! Just hold on, alright? I'm coming.
坚持住
Just hold on. Hold on.
再见
Bye-bye.
准备好
Brace yourself!
总统先生 你看起来帅爆了
You look damn good, Mr. President,
但你得把战衣还给我
but I'm gonna need that suit back.
总统安全了 托尼 我要撤了
The President is secure, Tony. I'm clearing the area.
干得好
Nice work.
- 准备好了吗 先生？ - 你什么意思？
- Ready sir? - What do you mean "Ready"?
珮珀 我来了 放松 我在这 看着我就行了
Pep, I got you. Relax, I got you. Just look at me.
亲爱的 我手只能伸这么远
Honey, I can't reach any further,
你也不能呆在那 明白么？
and you can't stay there, alright?
你得松手
You gotta let go.
你得松开手 我会拉住你的 我保证
You gotta let go. I'll catch you, I promise.
真丢人呀 是我的话就抓住她了
What a shame, I would have caught her.
弹出
Eject.
很好 我们到了屋顶
Well here we are, on the roof.
- 42代回程 - 我真够吃惊的
- Mark 42 inbound. - Well I'll be damned.
浪子回归了
The prodigal son returns.
不要在意
Whatever.
你真的配不上她 托尼
You really didn't deserve her, Tony.
实在遗憾啊 我就差那么一点就能让她 完美
It's a pity. I was so close to having her... perfect.
好好 等等等等 慢点慢点
Okay, okay, wait, wait, slow down, slow down.
你说得对 我配不上她
You're right. I don't deserve her.
但是有一点你错了
But here's where you're wrong.
她本来就很完美
She was already perfect.
贾维斯 帮我个忙 炸掉42代
Jarvis, do me a favor and blow Mark 42.
不要啊啊啊!!
Noooo!!
不再用假面了
No more false faces.
你说你想要找曼达林
You said you wanted the Mandarin.
你正看着他
You're looking right at him.
一直都是我 托尼 从一开始就是
It was always me, Tony, right from the start.
我就是曼达林!
I am the Mandarin!
我没武装
I got nothing.
贾维斯 在我12点方向的对象不是目标 取消目标!
Jarvis, subject at my 12 o'clock is not a target, disengage!
怎么？ 啊怎么了？ 你生我气了？
What? Oh what, are you mad at me?
亲爱的
Honey.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
我刚才真够暴力的
I was really violent.
你刚才吓死我了 我还以为你..
You just scared the devil out of me. I thought you were
以为我死了 为什么？ 因为我从200英尺高摔下去？
I was dead. Why? Because I fell two hundred feet?
- 现在咱俩谁糟糕点？ - 有待商榷
- Who's the hot mess now?  - Still debatable.
可能性有点向你倾斜了
Probably tipping your way a little bit.
你在家为什么不这么穿？
Why don't you dress like this at home?
嗯？ 运动文胸 这一整套
Hmm? Sports bra, the whole deal.
知道么 我现在明白
You know I think I understand
为什么你不愿意放弃你的战衣了
why you don't want to give up the suits.
我现在还能抱怨什么？
What I am gonna complain about now?
没事 有我呢 我会想出办法的
Well, it's me. I'll think of something.
- 别碰我 别 我会烫伤你的! - 没 没事
- Don't touch me. No, I'm gonna burn you!  - No, no.
你不烫
You're not hot.
我能变正常么？
Am I gonna be okay?
不会 你和我在一起
No, you're in a relationship with me,
什么事都不会正常的
everything will never be okay.
不过我想我能搞定这个 对
But I think I can figure this out, yeah.
我20年前喝醉时差点就能算出来了
I almost had this 20 years ago when I was drunk.
我能让你恢复的
I think I can get you better.
我就干这行的 专事修复
That's what I do. I fix things.
那你那些让你分心的家伙呢？
And all your distractions?
呃 我会稍稍削减他们的数量的
Uh, I'm gonna shave them down a little bit.
- 贾维斯 喂 - 都准备好了先生
- Jarvis, hey. - All wrapped up here, sir.
还有什么要做的么？
Will there be anything else?
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
先生 执行"清空历史"命令吗？
The "Clean slate" Protocol, sir?
去他的 今天是圣诞 没错 是的
Screw it, it's Christmas. Yes, yes.
那现在呢？ 你喜欢么？
Okay so far? You like it?
很满意
It'll do.
于是 随着圣诞早晨的到来
And so, as Christmas morning began,
我的旅程也到了终点
my journey had reached its end.
做一件事 开始时 不带目的 满怀热情
You start with something pure, something exciting.
然而接踵而来的是各种错误
Then come the mistakes.
还有妥协
The compromises.
我们创造自己的魔鬼
"We create our own Demons".
如同我承诺过的 我修理好了珮珀
As promised, I got Pepper sorted out.
敲打了一会儿
It took some tinkering.
但之后我又想到 为什么要止步于此？
But then I thought to myself. Why stop there?
自然会有人说进步是危险的
Of course, there are people who say progress is dangerous.
但我打赌这群傻子里没一个人
But I'll bet none of those idiots
曾带着满胸腔的弹片活着
ever had to live with a chest full of shrapnel.
不过现在开始… 我也不会了
And now... neither will I.
我告诉你 那是这么多年来我睡得最好的一次
Let me tell you, that was the best sleep I'd had in years.
- 没事的 没事的 - 别!
- It's okay, it's okay.  - No!
如果要我漂亮地总结一番这故事
So if I were to wrap this up tight with a bow or whatever.
我会说 我的战衣从来不是分心的玩意 也不是爱好
I guess I'd say my armor was never a distraction or a hobby.
它是个茧
It was a cocoon.
现在 我破茧而出 焕然一新
And now, I'm a changed man.
你可以夺走我的房子
You can take away my house,
也可以拿走我的小把戏小玩具
All my tricks and toys.
但你夺不走的是
One thing you can't take away...
我就是钢铁侠
I am Iron Man.
《钢铁侠3》
知道么 谢谢你听我倾诉
You know, and thank you, by the way, for listening.
这真的很有用 把郁积心头的话都说出来
There's just something about getting it off my chest
敞开心扉 一吐为快
and putting it out there in the atmosphere instead of holding this in.
久郁成疾 你知道么？
I mean, this is what gets people sick, you know?
哇 之前都不知道你这么擅长倾听
Wow, I had no idea you were such a good listener.
能和人分享所有我的
To be able to share all
想法和经历
of my intimate thoughts and my experiences
让我的压力直降一半
with someone, it just cuts the weight of it in half, you know.
就像蛇吞咬自己的尾巴
It's like a snake swallowing its own tail.
所有事都画上了圆满的圈
Everything comes full circle.
而且 而且你还帮我梳理了…
And...and the fact that you've been able to help me process...
- 那 呃… - 你还在听么？
- So, uh... - You with me?
我在 呃嗯 我们… 呃 你刚才说到… 呃
I was, yeah. Mm-hmm. We were... uh, we were at, uh...
你睡着了？
You actively napping?
我…我只是 我…我走神了
I...I was...I... I... I drifted.
从什么地方开始的？
Where did I lose you?
从你在瑞士进电梯开始
Elevator in Switzerland.
所以你什么都没听到？
So you heard none of it?
我很抱歉 我不是那种医生
I'm sorry, I'm not that kind of doctor.
我不是治疗师 没受过相关训练
I'm not a therapist, it's not my training.
- 那是？ - 我没有…
- So?  - I don't have the...
- 没什么？ 没时间？ - 那种好脾气
- What? The time? - Temperament.
你知道么 现在我再回头想想
You know what? Now that I think about it,
噢对 我最早的伤疤 1983年 对吧？
Oh God my original wound. 1983, alright?
是的
Yes.
那时我都14岁了 还有保姆照看？ 真怪异
I'm 14 years old, I still have a nanny? That was weird.